Heat. Heat. N.
[Music]
Hey,
hey, hey.
[Music]
Heat.
Hello everybody. Good day, good evening
everybody and welcome to the ask show.
Hope everybody is doing great. Uh as I'm
sure you know today is a super chat
episode and live chat episode. We'll
take as many as many questions from the
super chat as possible and also from the
live chat as and when possible. And
today is a geopolitics only episode. So
let's take questions about geopolitics.
Let me see who is there on the live chat
and let us see who all is there. I can
see strainus something uh Alan J. Victor
Sabatraati Nabarita Das Sergeant Skylan
Somi Jin Animals for laugh good evening
Aayush Singh Namaste Rohan Sunja Vikash
PJ Shashi Kiran Abi Abi Silva Sachin
Shaw Dhaj Kamat good morning Amaya Tulp
from Germany hello Barat first Dakwa
from Gujarat hello Samriati hello Amisha
hi Amisha Mishra hello Dorya crazy brain
hello good to see you again Rakkesh
Mistri Shashi Kiran um Baskar Kayatwal
Jade Parmar Aayush again Mahik Kata from
Ethiopia. Hello Dakshwara is from Raj
Rajot Gujarat Sumit Bat First uh Sparti
Uturi Namaste Bat again Negro
Geopolitical Dubai from Indor Hello good
evening prane Paul from Kolkata Raja
Akash Kumar good evening Vladimir Putin
Aayushman Singh Varun Baj from Twitter
or or X Raghav Raj Banga Master Diddi
Yatinda
General Subutai Napoleon Singh Shikawad
is going to Russia. Suhas Ready Hy
Penguin Pratik Magdum
Prat Pratik Tagare Niha from China.
Mlavin from Hawaii. Kuml Prabhakar Pande
Nav Bagalc Court Arjun from Oceanana
Stone from Mumbai and so many other
people. So good evening, good day to all
of you. Thank you so much for being on
the live chat. And let us take some
questions. What questions do we have? Uh
I can see Ganesh from Germany as well.
Adita Radi and everybody else. U Sasha
Shalavik from shalom from Tel Aviv.
Well, shalom back to you sir and
everybody else. Okay. So, let's take
some questions. All right. So, this is
the first question we will take. Rohan
Suna asks, "What's my views on the
Azarbaijan Armenia peace deal by DT by
Donald Trump?" Aharbaijan Armenia. Yes.
So Donald Trump has has negotiated has
brokered a peace deal between the two
nations Azarbaijan and Armenia who have
been at loggerheads for a very long
time. Uh historically the region okay
let's go to the maps and let's put the
map on the screen. Uh this is the region
we are talking about. Let's get that on
the screen. So we are talking about the
Kavkas region, the Kasus region and here
we have the nations Azarbaijan, Armenia,
Georgia and Russia.
So the two nations have been at
loggerheads for a very long time. Both
were part of the USSR and after the USSR
broke up, there was a war over Nagoro
Karabak or Arsak that region. Um and at
least two wars. There was one in 1991,
there was one in 2020 and that's been
you know simmering and still going on
kind of for some time for the past four
five years on and off. Um and in the
last war, the 2020 war, Azarbaijan
gained significant amounts of territory
from Armenia. Uh essentially the
objective is to wipe Armenia off the map
of the world to to erase Armenia from
the map of the world and to create a pan
panuric corridor between Turkey,
Azarbaijan and the Turk nations like
Turkmanistan etc. A long story I will
not tell you about the the entire
history but that's the deal. So
Azarbaijan is in the is in the
ascendancy and Donald Trump has brokered
a peace deal between the two nations. So
there's going to be an end to
hostilities between the two nations.
Both countries have committed to seize
all fighting, respect each other's
sovereignty, open diplomatic and uh
trade relations etc. And the interesting
thing is that this agreement it grants
the United States exclusive development
rights for a 27m corridor which is going
to be the which is going to be called
the Trump route.
the Trump route for international peace
and prosperity and this will be a route
across southern Armenia and it's going
to uh connect Azarbaijan with the with
this exclave that they have. Yeah. Nak
nakchiban
uh which borders Turkey and the US will
have exclusive development rights to
this place. There's going to be rail,
there's going to be oil and gas
pipelines, electricity, data lines, what
not. So there's a commercial angle to
this and Mr. Trump is going to uh well
the US is going to benefit from that. So
that essentially is is the long and the
short of the thing and uh both nations
have signed this peace agreement. Mr.
Trump has brokered it. He's the
peacemaker. He wants a Nobel Peace Prize
come what may, right?
Uh so the question is how long will this
last? Well, I suppose it will last. If
Mr. Trump is personally invested
interested in this. He's going to ensure
that this is enforced
and we'll see. See, Mr. Trump is around
is going to be around as the president
for the of the US for the next three and
a half years. After that, we'll see how
it goes. But I expect that it's going to
last at least as long as Mr. Trump is in
power, as long as he is a reasonably
strong president, which remains to be
seen. So that's my views so far. It's a
it's a very new event and yeah that's
what's happened thus far.
Goldliness says rank top five world
leaders based on their IQ and foreign
policy style from 1950 till now. Also as
an Indian I want to nominate Mr. Cha for
Padma. Well that's very kind of you.
Thank you so much. Uh rank the top five
world leaders on their IQ. Well, I would
I I don't know what the IQs of the
various leaders were, but we can uh rank
leaders based on how successful they
were. And how do you measure how
successful a leader is? Well, the only
that's a good question actually. What's
the parameter that you b that you rank
leaders on? Well, the only parameter
that counts is whether a leader succeeds
or not in ensuring their nation's peace,
prosperity, and success overall. Right?
the achievement of your national uh
national objectives of your foreign
policy objectives, economic objectives
and overall an increase in your national
prosperity, security, all of that.
So from 1950 until now who were the
great world leaders? Let us see. I think
Joseph Stalin was one of the great
leaders. You know he did very nasty
things. No question about it. Right. Um
terribly terribly nasty things he did.
But overall you could you have to give
Mr. Stalin credit for transforming the
USSR from a broken country into a
superpower.
So number one is Joseph Stalin. You see
when you talk about these things you
geopolitical rankings and all this is
pretty amoral. You don't inject morality
into this. You don't bring morality into
the discourse. So you have someone like
Mahatong. You have someone like Joseph
Stalin. They did terrible terrible
things that caused the deaths of
millions. But still if you look at the
overall trajectory that a nation took
after as as a consequence of their rule
it was overall beneficial you could say
from a numerical perspective hard power
score the hard power score of the USSR
increased substantially
so one would be Mr. started the second I
suppose you would have to give it
okay we're talking about dictators here
I suppose what would be maong you know
he did terrible things I mean the great
leap forward the green the cultural
revolution the war on sparrows in case
you haven't heard about that look it up
the war on sparrows which caused a
frightening frightful famine in China
and yet
he Maung was responsible for China
gaining this gigantic piece of land
called Tibet, right? They still occupy
Tibet. Maong ensured that China got an
upper hand over India decisively 1962
and so much more. So much more maong. So
I would have to give it to Maong. So
that's another one. That's two. Who
else? Um US presidents Lynden Johnson.
Well, he brought the deep state back.
You could say Lynden Johnson, but I
would so I would say it would be Ronald
Reagan, the last great American
president. He's the one who presided
over the
essentially the dissolution of the USSR.
So I would say um Ronald Reagan. Who
else do we have? One would be I would
say Lee Kuanu. Uh benevolent dictator, a
strong man. uh he did not brookke any
descent or whatsoever but but he
transformed this little city state
called Singapore from a third world
nation third world backwater to a first
world nations in just one generation 20
25 years amazing incredible thing um
there's one slot left who do we bring in
should we bring in I don't know there's
there's there's no one from Africa that
I can think of and they were good people
but they were all well bumped off by the
by whoever by the powers that
Um, who else is it? Mr. Shald.
Um, was he that impactful? Mr. Sha de
Gaul. Um, any I would say Margaret
Thatcher, probably. Margaret Thatcher,
the the iron lady of the UK. There's
plenty of people who dislike her, but
overall, she as long as she was in
power, the the UK was still
a world power.
It was not a lap dog of the US. The
moment she went out of power, the within
five years the US, the UK became a lap
dog of the US utterly. The moment Tony
Blair comes to power, right? So, I would
say Margaret Thatcher. I'm sure there's
more leaders, but here we have it. Five
leaders since you asked for. I will not
rank them which is the first, which is
second, but these are the five I can
think of off the top of my head of my
head.
All right. Sergeant Skylin says, "Why
has Trump been antagonistic towards us
India since operation Sidhur?" Uh, by
the way, proud that our India is
standing up for itself. No question
about it. It's something to be really
proud of. Most would have expected that
India would cave in that India would
bend the knee and become a de facto
vasal of the US. If you if you have
watched my geost strategy episodes, you
will see that I had given four scenarios
on the 1st of July, the kind of
trajectory the US India relationship
could possibly take. Four scenarios. One
was India standing up for itself. Second
was India becoming a vasal. Um third was
India not doing really well, not being
here there just just you know things not
going well for India. And the fourth one
was a tilt towards China.
So it's the and the first one was India
gets a good deal with the US. Yeah,
there was there was option A scenario A,
scenario B was India becomes a vasal.
Scenario C was India stands up for
itself and scenario D was a tilt towards
China. So we are witnessing something
like scenario C and a little bit of
sprinkling of scenario C. Uh scenario D.
So India standing up for itself.
Incredible. I think it's shocked a lot
of people around the world. I think
Trump himself is rather stunned as to
how things have gone. The the the turn
the relationship has taken. So why has
Trump been antagonistic towards us?
Well, the US, I will say this again,
regards India as a problem. They do not
want the emergence of a new China down
the line, 20 years on the line by 2035,
2040 horizon. And India is showing every
sign of doing that. Despite all the
immense internal problems India has,
India faces problems of our our own
making.
Despite all the internal problems, India
is still the fastest growing uh major
economy in the world and India is
projected to keep on growing. There's no
chance of recession no matter what
happens. So by 2035 2040, India is going
to be a whole different beast, a
different league altogether. And the US
doesn't want that. The US believes that
they can deal with China. But they want
to contain India. They want to keep
India down. They want to um hamper
whatever chances India has of growing.
So that is one and Trump is the guy
who's changing the entire world order.
So obviously he's going to focus on
India. And secondly, something happened
during operation Synindhur. Clearly some
things have been revealed yesterday like
we knocked out five Pakistani fighter
planes. We destroyed multiple F-16s on
the ground. We clearly have hit nuclear
warhead storage sites where you would
have nuc US nuclear warheads being
stored there not Pakistani ones. We hit
their Nurhan air base which was operated
by the US. It has come out that that
that revelation has come out. Um and
maybe some other things also happened
and it looks like there was a phone call
between Mr. Modi and Mr. Trump and Mr.
Trump probably must have made some
threats and Mr. Modi would have it looks
like Mr. Modi did not stand down. He
stood he stood up for India and I think
that's where the relationship changed
right so Trump is really upset Trump
wants India to bend the knee and become
become a proper American wasal and
that's not happening so that's why he is
being antagonistic towards us and that's
going to continue so the India US
relationship is going downhill and
that's not going to change anytime soon
Kamat says aren't Trump's policies
endangering the US's imperial interests.
Trump is basically compelling countries
to collectively unite to reduce their
dependence on the US. The EU is now
pursuing military sovereignty. You are
right. I mean, if you have seen my past
past Jewish strategy episodes, you will
see that the EU is is doubling its uh uh
military spending and it's taking many
steps that can be regarded as uh steps
that will boost its strategic autonomy
visa with the US which would make it
less of a vasal of the US overall, EU,
NATO, all of that. You know, things are
changing. So, the question is what on
earth is Trump doing? Isn't what he is
doing? Isn't that endangering the the
US's imperial interests overall? What
are the US's imperial interests? To hold
as many nations as vasals as possible
and to have complete uh 360deree power
production capabilities across the
globe. These are the US interests right
now. By dismantling the global trade
order, the global financial, monetary,
economic order and going back to the
good old days of the imperial system
when you dealt with countries one by one
rather than having a broad treaty broad
superructure the rules-based world order
which applied to everybody and you let
things roll rule. Uh he has totally
shaken up the world order and a lot of
countries obviously aren't aren't happy
with this. I mean you you had an
existing relationship that was going
just fine. The entire world was running
smoothly. But now you've dismantled
everything and you're imposing tariffs
one by one on countries depending on how
they deal with you and whether they show
sufficient difference or not. What does
this indicate? What does it indicate? It
indicates that the US is no longer
confident about it itself. It created
this world order that existed until um
earlier this year the first quarter of
the year and now it's dismantling it.
Right? It's uh Mr. Trump is uh the guy
who's in charge of dismantling this. So
the US created the order that was
running smoothly all this while but now
they want to dismantle it. Why is it?
It's because they feel that they are no
longer that powerful overall. There are
major powers that are rising now and
that and these powers pose significant
challenges to the US. The kind of
challenges the US hasn't seen in
essentially forever. Right? Essentially
since 1990991
when the USSR disintegrated the USSR was
kind of an equal to the US it was a peer
competitor and now you have the the
since the 2012 or so you have the
emergence of China u and you have now
the the emergence of India as well.
India is also a nation that could in 20
years become another China kind of
entity different but similar uh and
overall the US its economy I mean if you
look at the economy of the G7 nations
and compare that with the BIRC nations
you can see bricks is now taking over so
there's so much happening that is making
the US way less confident uh China is
rising technologically China has be
become an almost peer competitor of the
US in so many technologies um and so
much more so the US isn't
confident now. It's it's worried and
that's why they want to gain more
control over the world order by
dismantling what exists and and
approaching every relationship as a
bilateral relationship and deciding
based on negotiations how much tariffs
to impose on on which nation and the
nations that don't cowtow will be hit
with major tariffs, massive tariffs like
India, like like Brazil and so on.
So it looks like Trump believes that
this is going to work for him, right?
And Trump is somebody who has been
speaking about tariffs for 20 30 years.
I mean I I've seen interviews of Trump
when he was nowhere near being a
politician. He had not even considered
being a politician but he was asked
about the the way the US deals with
various nations and he said that we
should impose tariffs about tariffs. He
used to talk about tariffs like 20 30
years ago. So this has always been one
of his pet projects and now he is he's
implementing that. So he personally
seems to believe that I am um paternal
preternaturally intelligent person and I
understand the way the world works. I
understand everything and I'm going to
get things done. I'm going to you know
bring the US back on top again. I'm
going to make America great again. But
is it going to work? Well, are you
already seeing a backlash towards that?
Lots of I mean everyone's unhappy with
this. The US people are nations are
cooperating with the US because they are
afraid of the US because the US is the
number one super it's a superpower. But
nobody likes this. No one likes this.
And when it comes to nations like India,
China, Russia, Brazil, etc. They're
going to clearly band together. It's
going to happen in some some shape form
or or way. It's going to happen. So So
that's one thing that's going that that
is going to be the consequence of what
Trump is doing. A lot of nations are
going to coalesce in a different
in in in a grouping that is essentially
not aligned with the US which
essentially means opposed to the US and
when major economies like China, India,
Russia, Brazil, they all come together
and ma and other nations are also drawn
towards that that becomes a problem.
That's the number that's the first
problem one can think of and this is
going to have long-term consequences.
later they can't say well let's go back
to the old old world order because this
is not working out that won't work again
later and secondly the tariffs are going
to bite Trump in his backside very badly
because it's not us who's paying the
tariffs it's the American companies and
American public that's paying the
tariffs that's what the people of
America now beginning to suddenly
realize right so if I am an American
importer I'm an American corporation and
I am importing goods from India. Let's
say I'm importing a million dollars
worth of let's say coconuts. Okay, let's
worth of coconuts from India. But the US
but Trump has imposed 50% tariffs on
Indian goods. So when I receive the
shipment worth a million dollars from
India, the moment I receive the
shipment, I'm going to have to pay that
shipment is worth a million dollars,
right? So I'm going to have to pay 50%
tariffs on that. I'm the importer. I'm
the American company. I'm going to have
to pay half a million dollars to the US
government on on receipt of the goods
either to customs or or whoever
whichever entity it is in whichever
shape or form. So I the importer of the
American company am paying the tariff to
the US government
and then since I have paid 50% tariffs
I'm going to have to sell this goods to
my to my consumers the to the US
population at 50% at a 50% hiked rate.
Otherwise, I'm going to be at a big
loss. So, who's going to essentially pay
the price? I, the American company, am
paying the price and the American
consumer is paying the price. It's going
to cause a rise in prices. It eventually
can boost manufacturing or whatever
locally in the US, but it is going to
create havoc in the US. Trump's approval
ratings are going to plummet
and the midterms which happen probably
next year, it's going to be severe for
the Republicans. That's what I foresee
right now.
So, Trump is going to it's not it's not
going to um it's not going to be all
smooth for Trump. He's going to be in
very soon in rocky waters. So, yeah,
overall you can see that this is going
to weaken the US. So, I agree with you.
It's going to weaken the US. It's going
to weaken the US geopolitically. It's
going to weaken the US uh
internationally, diplomatically, and
it's going to weaken Trump's position
internally, domestically, politically,
all of that.
And
well,
someone of Trump's intelligence not
seeing this. I don't know. Uh Barbar
says, "Podcast with Dr. Sha, your
views." Um
um yeah, I am not aware of his analysis,
so don't know. Sorry.
Uh Vishal says once you said something
like China can take try to take Taiwan
in 2027 or before 2027 why so look I
said that there seems to be some kind of
deadline that has given to his armed
forces which is uh the PLA and whatever
else people's liberation army it it
looks like he has given a deadline of
2027 that you need to be ready fully
ready and fully prepared by 2027 to take
Taiwan when I give the orders.
So, and and we know that uh the the
situation has changed significantly
across the the Taiwan Strait. Uh the
PLA, the patterns of its exercises,
etc., they've increased significantly.
The overflights over Taiwan, the
intrusions into Taiwanese waters, the
encircling of the island, all of that
has increased in frequency and magnitude
and whatnot. um the past let's say three
four years right uh by in in 2020 2021
the situation was very different so you
can see a significant uptick increase in
the intensity and magnitude and
frequency of these military actions that
the the Chinese armed forces are
undertaking around Taiwan. So they
clearly have taken some kind of deadline
seriously and they are yeah preparing
they're doing military uh exercises and
and mock drills and whatnot for an
invasion.
So yeah it looks like there's a deadline
of 2027 and that's why I said that but
we'll see how it goes.
Napoleon Singh Shiki Khawat says why
can't India use its NRIs big ones India
favor Cash Patel see cash Patel is not a
non-resident Indian he is a US citizen a
non-resident Indian is a person who
lives outside of India but is still a an
Indian citizen holds an Indian passport
Kasha Patel Cash Patel the director of
the FBI is a US citizen
so well if he has a US citizen, he's
going to work for the interests of the
United States naturally. Uh
and we have lots of Indian origin people
in in significant positions in the US.
No question about it. Uh if you look at
the Fortune 500 companies, if you look
at the big tech companies, Microsoft,
Google, Microsoft, you have Mr. Satya
Nadilla, uh Google, you have Mr. Sundar
Pichai and and so many more. But these
are all US citizens.
None of them are Indian citizens as far
as I know. And if you're a US citizen,
you're going to work for your country.
You're not going to work for India. And
of course, we have a huge diaspora in
the in the US and other countries. And
I'm sure that they can be well, they
will still have feelings for India. So,
you can certainly uh perhaps tap into
that in some shape or form, but you
don't do that overtly. You never do that
overtly. The Chinese have a full-fledged
program of doing that and the Americans
are really really worried about Chinese
origin citizens in the US. Anyhow,
that's how it is.
Zishan says, "If Putin gets to keep the
five oblasts, would that justify
everything Russia has lost in the war or
will the Russian public demand more?"
Um, right. So, what's the situation
right now? Uh how many oblasts uh does
uh Ukrainian oblasts does Russia control
right now? Is it five? Uh we know that
it's Luhans donets those regions. So
let's go to the map quickly. Um let's go
to the map. So Russia controls about
between 1/5 to 1/4 of uh the nation of
Ukraine. Um definitely the Luhansk
Donetsk region. Mario is it definitely
I'm not sure. Odessa not not thisa but
yeah overall a significant portion of
Ukraine is controlled and look Mr. Putin
is now going to u meet with Mr. Trump in
Alaska right that's that's been
announced so Mr. Putin will meet with
with Mr. Trump for um a summit
a first round of negotiations let's say
let's say uh about potentially ending
the Ukraine war so Trump is desperate
Mr. Trump is desperate to end the UK
Ukraine war. He had promised that he
would end it on day one of his
presidency. It's it's been a big failure
uh from that perspective. So Mr. Trump
is desperate and Mr. Putin knows that
Mr. Trump is desperate. Now you want to
negotiate from a position of strength
and Mr. Putin has a huge amount of
leverage because he controls so much of
territory that his armed forces have
taken over at his command and I expect
that Mr. Putin knowing Mr. Trump's
negotiating negotiation style, Mr. Putin
will come out with initially maximalist
demands. I would say it would involve
the complete demilitarization of
Ukraine, the complete dennazification of
Ukraine, a regime change in Kiev and
more territory for Russia beyond what it
control currently controls. Maybe
territory all the way to the Niper
River. I don't know. I expect Mr. Putin
to make maximalist demands straight off
the bat, right? And then let's see how
Mr. Trump responds. So Putin, I assure
you, whatever territory his armed forces
currently control, not an inch is going
to be given away. He's going to demand
more
because he justifiably can say, I can
unleash hell tomorrow.
Okay? I I can flatten Ukraine on on on
demand if if required. He his armed
forces have the capability to flatten
Ukraine. They've been extremely
restrained. They've purposefully chosen
a slow war strategy, a frozen conflict
strategy because eventually the major
victories come on the negotiating table.
So you've got to prepare the groundwork
for that and that's uh what's going to
happen now. So Putin will definitely
keep whatever territory the Russians
have already taken and he's going to
demand more and at the end of the day
whenever a negotiated settlement happens
it's going to be more territory that
Russia will gain. That's how I see
things going. Mr. Zalinski obviously
is going to say he doesn't accept this
and that's going to be a problem. That's
going to be a problem not for Mr. Putin
but for Mr. Trump.
Okay. Uh now will the Russian public be
satisfied with five blasts? Um I think
they will be satisfied even if Russia
gets five blasts because Russia has
already but the I I'm pretty sure the
Russian public will be expecting a
regime change in Ukraine. Zalinsky can't
continue. So these are the hard demands
Mr. Putin will make on Mr. Trump and the
onus is going to be on Mr. Trump. Mr.
Trump is going to be be the defensive is
going to be on the defensive. is not in
a position to go on the offensive and to
sweeten the deal, Putin may give some
kind of uh you know carrot to Mr. Trump.
You get to um you know uh exploit some
resources of Ukraine or whatever you
know obviously that sort of thing is
very enticing for Mr. Trump as we know
very well. So that's how I see things
going. I see Putin keeping all the
territory he has acquired. I see Putin
asking for way more territory and asking
for way more than simply territory.
Denuclear de d de d de d de d de d de d
de d de d de d de d dem
milmilitarization dnazification regime
change and much more. And I think that's
how it's going to go. And I don't think
the first summit will see an end of the
war. Maybe they will need more meetings.
They'll need more meetings. the first
meeting. I don't think any any viable
result will come from that because it's
not up to these two gentlemen. There's
another factor which is Mr. Zalinski and
the fact that the EU supports Mr.
Zalinski and Mr. Trump doesn't control
the EU that much. So that's going to be
a problem. So Mr. Trump is going to be
on the defensive and it's going to be a
big headache for him as to what to do
about Mr. Zalinski.
May well we'll see about that. Yeah. All
right.
Mayang says after AIF F-35 PM statements
what more can India do? What's AIF?
F-35 I understand. What's AIF? PM
statement.
Um I am I'm a little confused as to what
AIF means. AIF F-35. We know we are not
buying the F-35 for sure.
That's that's off the table now because
uh the US can't be trusted. When you
when they support Pakistan, how can we
trust them, right? So the F-35 is
obviously off the table. We're not
purchasing that. We'll most likely go
with it looks like possibly the the
Sukoy 57. Yeah. Uh as long as there's
proper significant transfer of
technology and so on. I'm not sure what
AIF means. I'm sorry about that. All
right. Sorry. Okay. Prashant says per
Kissinger
being America's friend is dangerous.
Being an enemy is fatal. Not so not not
quite the case.
Not he didn't say being an enemy is
fatal. What did he say?
Being America's friend is dangerous.
Being an ally is fatal. What exactly did
Kissinger say? Let's let's let's Google
it. I am oldfashioned. I don't do chat
GPD. I I do Google. Kissinger. Okay,
let's let's uh see Kissinger's
statement.
Being America's friend, it's ah this is
the one. It may be dangerous to be
America's enemy, but to be America's
friend is fatal. Understand? It may be
dangerous to be America's enemy, but to
be America's friend is fatal. That's
what Mr. the Kissinger said.
Okay,
so
you see being a friend is fatal.
Being an enemy is dangerous, no
question. But being a friend is fatal.
So can you think of America's friends
today? NATO nations, EU nations, South
Korea, Japan, essentially vasals and
countries under American occupation. And
Canada couldn't be considered to be an
American friend and so on. um enemy. We
aren't an enemy of the US. You could say
China and Russia are America's enemies.
India is from Trump's perspective a
prospective vasal, a nation that he
would like to add to the ranks of his
vasals. That's the thing. That's what he
wants. He wants to make India America's
friend. And we are refusing to be a
friend. And we are also refusing to be
an enemy. We are we are on the middle
ground. We are saying we are not your
enemy. We have no interest in being an
enemy of the US. We want to cooperate
with you wherever possible. Wherever it
is mutually beneficial, we want to
cooperate with you and we have been
doing that thus far.
Right? So we do not have any interest in
being your enemy. We will do nothing
that will harm your interests. But we
will safeguard our interests. And if you
insist that we take actions that harm
our interests, we will refuse point
blank to your face. That's India's
stand. We are not bending the knee. We
are not caving in. We are not agreeing
to become an American vasal.
Over here friend means understand that.
So we don't want to be in that position.
That's fatal. That's fatal.
But we won't be your enemy. Nope. We
won't do a thing that will hurt you, but
we will safeguard our interests. That's
where we are. That's the middle ground.
Understand? We are keeping our interests
safe. We are prioritizing our interests.
We are working to um towards our
interests and we are staying cautious.
We are doing nothing that can genuinely
be regarded as something that is
adversarial
to the US or detrimental to US
interests. So I think that's that's the
right strategy for India and that's
exactly what we're doing. Very good
foreign policy. I don't care what so and
so people are saying about India's
foreign policy. I have no interest in in
in who
whatever so and so person is saying.
This is my perspective. I have some
understanding of how things work.
So yeah,
Bradley says, "Could Trump use the
Kashmir issue to sanction India?"
How so? How so? What What is it that
merits sanctioning? What are we doing in
Kashmir? What exactly?
There's no justification.
See, when you want to sanction a nation,
you need some kind of justification.
It's some kind of some kind of pretext.
Well, what is it that we are doing in
Kashmir
that would justify any any any form of
sanctions? There's nothing they can
find. That's the problem they're facing,
right?
Um, so yeah, they they can't really, of
course, if they want to do it, then they
can make any kind of pretext, any kind
of justification, but we are not there
yet in that relationship where they will
start sanctioning us. See in the past
the US sanctioned India when we tested
nuclear weapons. We are a sovereign
nation. We have the right to do whatever
we wish that is in line with our
perception of our national security,
national interests and that's what we
did. Prime Minister Waj ordered the
testing of nuclear weapons and we tested
them and as a consequence the Americans
imposed sanctions on India that you
cannot do such things. You cannot dare
become a nuclear power. Well we are one
now. Deal with it. So they imposed
sanctions on India and at that time the
USSR had just uh disintegrated. So the
Americans arm twisted Russia into not
selling not transferring cryogenic
rocket engine technology to India. So
India had to
work another decade to develop the
technology inhouse but we did that. So
if they really want to sanction India
they'll find any pretext. But I don't
see Kashmir being that pretext.
A board soul still says will Trump make
statements over Kashmir now it's
possible he may Trump Trump may try to
needle India in a multiplicity of ways
and one of those could be possibly
making statements over Kashmir I mean
he's definitely cozying up with Pakistan
he is getting Pakistan in bed with him
right Aim Munir the the the military
whatever he is dictator of Pakistan he I
think he's currently on a on a second
visit to the US in like two three
months. So he's being given the red
carpet treatment by the Trump regime and
if they're in bed with Pakistan they may
they may make statements over Kashmir.
Well, we'll see about that. Yes. Nikil
Shvastav says if the US and India start
opposing each other, how will India
carry out its ambitions in AI, GPUs,
LLM, etc. Will we miss the bus?
Yep, it's a good question.
So look, India isn't opposing the US,
but India is opposing US attempts to
vasalize India and that is a huge
affront to Mr. Trump. How dare you? How
dare you? You need to bend the knee. You
need to be super differential to me in
the sort of thing. Uh so the US is
opposing India. We aren't opposing the
US. Okay. So let's say the US opposes
India and and Trump is super super upset
with India, super pissed off with India,
let's say. And let's say he imposes
restrictions on exports of of
semiconductor products to India. The
kind of restrictions he has imposed on
China for example. Let's say he does
that. What does India do then? That's
that would place India put India in in a
in a in a spot definitely it will be bad
for India. What do we do then? So then
we will have to wait until our own
semiconductor mission becomes a little
more mature and starts producing chips
of of of that are more powerful. Right
now we are producing a certain class of
chips. It's just begun. But not bad. Not
bad. We have at least taken the initial
steps in the right direction. So maybe
we may have to dep to to either wait for
a decade until we start producing chips
of that caliber or maybe we'll have to
import something from China if China is
willing to do that. Will China be
willing to do do that? We'll have to
see. So you see this is what happens
when you are technologically not
sovereign enough. When you depend on
other nations for critical technologies.
So the so nations like the US will
definitely seek to leverage that.
So will we miss the bus? I don't think
we'll entirely miss the bus. See what
the government can do is whatever GPUs
etc do exist in the country they can be
uh stockpiled and given only to
uh
research efforts that are critical in
nature that sort of thing. So you know
rationing and stuff and we may still be
able to produce uh good enough AIS and
so on. We are working towards that
direction right now but it will
certainly hamper uh our plans. So this
is what happens when you're
technologically not sovereign. So we are
now beginning to take the steps in the
right direction towards becoming fully
sovereign in in in the field of
semiconductors and and um quantum
computing and all of that. So yeah it's
going to be a tough road ahead. Like I
said, India is going to have to swallow
20 years of pain and this could be one
one of one of those things. We will see.
The government of India will have to
come up with creative solutions, I
suppose, if if this sort of thing
happens, if the US imposes restrictions
on India.
Amisha says, "No questions, just want
you to know you're the best." Thank you
so much, ma'am. Thank you so much. Very
kind of you. Thank you.
Go says, "Can India stop all trade with
the US? Is it practically possible?"
Look, anything is practically possible,
but is is it is it something we want to
do? You see, the US is the world's
largest market, the largest consumer
market. Their population is what 330 or
so million people, give or take
something.
But their purchasing power is is second
to none. It's it's number one in the
world. So, the largest market that we
can export to is the US. And because of
that, it's it's something we would
definitely not want to do stopping trade
with them. then we would have to look
for alternative markets or we have to we
for our goods see our ambition is to
become a major manufacturing power right
right now the world is seeking to
diversify from China
so which nation can replace China as the
major manufacturer it's only India
obviously because of the scale that that
we have the huge population the huge
resources the huge size of of the nation
and so on so forth so we have to become
a manufacturing power But let but if if
we are in a situation where we can't
export to the US if we can't if we are
not doing any trade with the US then
where do we export to
all the goods we are manufacturing
then you can have alternative markets
like the EU the European Union which is
not a bad alternative it's not as big as
the US overall the EU is there so we
could potentially think of the EU but
that won't be the same as the US market
and another alternative is China. Well,
is China an import dependent market?
Absolutely not. They're an export
dependent market. They are the world's
largest manufacturer currently. Why
would they need to import anything? So,
China is out of the question. So then
what do we do with all the manufacturing
if we are setting up manufacturing?
We'll have to then depend on internal
consumption, domestic consumption. But
for that you need uh purchasing power
and whatnot which kind of we don't have
right now. So you know so that's why
it's best to not stop trade with the US
find some kind of negotiated uh deal
some kind of agreement with the US
whatever tariffs are mutually acceptable
or whatever so I think the negotiations
will continue and eventually hopefully
we we arrive at some kind of trade deal
with the US which which makes sense
which is hopefully mutually beneficial.
Govin says, "Can Russia afford to open
multiple fronts with uh Finland and
Poland?" I don't think Russia can afford
to do that. It makes no sense to fight
so many multiple enemies at the same
time. That's a mistake many
um leaders have done in the past.
Napoleon, he sought to fight everybody
at the same time. Everyone's my enemy. I
I'll fight everybody at the same time.
What happened?
Elba. Elba is what happened. Look it up.
Abel was I ear I saw Elba. Elba. The
island of Elba. And then St. Helena and
so on. So Napoleon, well, you see what
happened to him. Another example is the
great painter himself, the painter, the
Austrian painter. So the Austrian
painter, he also did something similar,
trying to fight everybody at the same
time. You're fighting the allies, you're
fighting the UK, you're fighting the
Americans. then you decide to start
operation Barbarosa and start start a
fight with Stalin as well. I mean how
many people can you fight at the same
time? You can't it's not a good it's not
a good idea. So I would say Russia
cannot afford to open multiple fronts
with at the same time with Finland and
Poland. They have to deal with Ukraine.
Ukraine is a proxy war. They are
fighting the entirety of NATO by proxy
essentially. It doesn't make sense for
them to open multiple fronts. So no
answer is no. Right.
Um Govin says perfect time for Thai for
China to take Taiwan. I am not sure
about that. Um
the US is too powerful and even if China
somehow does take Taiwan which is a
possibility they will take possession of
a destroyed burnt out island with no
nothing of real value. That's what will
happen. That's guaranteed. So what's the
point then? See, the the objective of
conquest is not to conquer a wasteland.
The objective of conquest is to conquer
something of value,
right? Otherwise, it's a hollow victory.
It's not really a victory. So, I'm not
sure if it's the perfect time for China
to take Taiwan. I don't think so. Not
yet. Not yet.
MK says, "Why is India focusing on chip
fabs but not developing EUV lithography
and EDA tools risking import bans like
the US imposed on China?"
Yeah, we do need to focus on lithography
photo lithography machines like what
ASML has. The Chinese are are developing
those machines that that technology.
Um what's EDA tools? I have to look into
that. What what are EDA tools? EDA
tools,
electronic design automation tools,
software suites used by engineers to
design, analyze and verify electronic
systems and circuits. Yep. All of this
is India needs to definitely develop all
of this photo lithography. What is EUV
lithography? EU V E U V lithography
ultra extreme ultra ultraviolet
lithography is is a form of
photoiththography obviously because
ultraviolet yeah
so it's something India needs to do you
can't take shortcuts you have to develop
the entire suite of technologies at the
same time which complement each other uh
I am not sure is India not what is India
doing is India developing let's let's
Google this together.
Is India is India
developing
developing lithography technology?
India is working to it's not currently
developing lithography technology
itself. The country is focused on
attracting foreign investment
collaborating with the canon. Well well
that's a problem. That's definitely a
problem.
So
yeah, I mean that that's that's not
enough.
That's not enough.
I I hope somebody in the government
wakes up and see and understands this
that all of this needs to be done. It's
not enough to just have chip fabs. You
need to develop these these technologies
at home. Only then are you genuinely uh
self-sufficient and technologically
sovereign. So I don't know why it's not
being done but it does need to be done
and hopefully somebody here listens and
hears this hopefully.
Rohan Sunija says do you think that
recent unemployment and job crisis in EU
is directly connected to the USA as the
US is de-industrializing Europe through
various means.
Look, what you have seen in Europe in
recent times is that their economy isn't
doing well in the EU nations, right?
Germany was in recession.
Um, I'm not sure what the economy is
like in Germany right now. I've not
looked at it, but yeah, the economy
isn't doing well. And that causes all
kinds of problems. Uh, unemployment, job
crisis, same thing. Yeah.
Um and the question is why is so so why
is the European economy not doing well?
So see the European economy is dependent
on Germany and France. Germany
especially Germany is the engine the
engine that drives the European economy.
Germany is a manufacturing power right
now. What do you need to have a massive
industrial base and sustain that and do
well? You need cheap energy. You need a
ready supply of cheap energy. That's
what powers an economy because all work
requires energy. All work requires
energy. Please remain remember this. Now
Germany was importing cheap natural gas
from Russia, wasn't it? Then what
happened? Nordstream was blown up, the
Nordstream 2 pipeline and u the flow of
gas ended
and Germany then started doing poorly
and it went into a recession.
So the US
essentially has has ensured that this
cheap energy that was flowing into
Europe from Russia which has plentiful
supplies of energy that cheap supply of
gas is no longer available. Right? So
that's one of the primary factors that
has led to all the problems that we are
seeing in Europe. So you could say that
Europe is kind of being
de-industrialized right now through
various means. Who's behind that? It
looks like maybe the US could be behind
that possibly. You could you could put
it that way. Possibly. Yes.
Sergeant Skylin says, "Well, this should
prove that our country is sovereign." No
question about it. No question.
What we are facing right now from the
US, it shows, it proves that our country
is sovereign.
Only sovereign countries face these
problems. If you are a vasal, you will
not face these problems. You will not be
treated like this because you're already
well, you know, you're taken care of. So
yes, this proves that India is a
sovereign nation. It's a sovereign
country. And I would like to commend the
government of India for standing up for
India and taking really tough decisions.
Geopolitical Dubai says full support
sir. Well, thank you so much sir. Thank
you.
Ji Parma Parmar says a Banglad terrorist
was found in Mizam. Park mischief.
Project K I would say. Project K is
cookie land for Christ. It's a it's a
project that was started by the Biden
regime and I suppose it's still
continuing. And one of the things the
Biden regime did was a regime change
operation successful in Bangladesh and
they ousted the democratically elected
prime minister Shikhasina and they've
put in a puppet government which is
which is a dictatorship essentially it's
a military dictatorship right and ever
since that happened Bangladesh
essentially became East Pakistan and
there's a significant amount of synergy
now between east and west Pakistan
so I had predicted at that time that we
should expect a an uptick in problems
emanating from Bangladesh you know
anti-India elements terrorists all of
that so if a Bangla terrorist was found
in Mizoram that's not surprising at all
not surprising at all because uh Misoram
is one of the pieces in the puzzle when
it comes to project K project K is this
project to create an artificial
Christian cookie nation out of Misoram
parts of Manipur parts of Bangladesh and
parts of Burma
and this is this is a project that is
being uh puppeteered from across from
the other side of the planet.
So I would not say it's park mischief.
It's mischief at a bigger scale way
bigger scale than Pakistan.
Ankita says Mr. Netanyahu has offered to
give tips to Mr. Modi on how to deal
with Mr. Trump. Should this be
considered seriously? I don't think Mr.
Modi needs anybody's tips on how to deal
with somebody. I think Mr. Modi can give
tips to whoever it is.
Really? I Let's Let's Google this. Has
Nathan Yahoo offered to give tips to Mr.
Modi? Let's see. Nathan Yu Modi, do we
have any will advise Prime Minister Modi
on how to deal with Trump?
Uh says Israel Prime Minister Netanyahu.
He's offered to help India in dealing
with 50% tariffs imposed by the US.
um
and he has called the basis of the US
India relationship very solid and urg
urged them to resolve whatever issues
exist. Can give Modi some advice.
Well
well what can we say? What can we say?
There is a special relationship that
exists between Israel and the United
States.
So
one could say that Mr. Netanyahu
would know how to let's say handle Mr.
Trump. Okay, that's all I'll say about
this. Uh
so yeah, Mr. Netanyahu definitely will
know how to handle Mr. Trump because he
would have certain forms of leverage,
let's say, but we don't have those forms
of leverage. So, it's a I would say it's
a very nice kind offer, a friendly
offer, but uh
I would say it's it's kind of a half
joking offer most likely.
Arun Mr. says, "Do you see China or
Russia taking offensive measures against
the US say like attack attacking their
territorial sovereignty and so on?" No,
I don't see that happening. No, that is
suicidal. Not going to happen anytime
soon.
Jadi Parmar says well I'm doing hope I'm
I'm doing well sir how are you I hope
you're doing well as well uh so Munir is
giving new threats to India aim
anti-India protest in New York by
immigrants immigrants well the US
finally has its mask off moment is the
war coming should India do next okay so
so the US is is unhappy with India see
India has refused to bend the knee to
cave in to kiss the ring and so on.
India has refused to vasalize itself and
become a US vasal and that has greatly
upset Mr. Trump and hurt his his
feelings. So Mr. Trump is using Pakistan
as a pressure point and obviously Mr.
Trump is heavily invested in Pakistan.
If you see my geo strategy videos you
will know how deeply Mr. Trump is
involved in Pakistan invested
personally.
So Mr. Moody is is Mr. Trump's blue-eyed
boy right now. Yeah, a favorite of Mr.
Trump. I mean he's been invited to the
US second time in like two three months.
So Mr. Mun is being given the red carpet
treatment and as such Mr. Mun is feeling
all emboldened. Yes, I can make strong
statements. I can defeat India verbally.
So he's making issuing statements like
if India builds a dam in in Kashmir then
we will wait for the dam to be built and
then we will uh what hit it with
missiles 10 missiles or something.
That's what I heard that he said. Um and
if there are anti-India protests in New
York, well those are obviously done with
the approval of the of the US uh
government obviously. So the US finally
has its maskoff moment like I've said
look the US seeks to contain India. The
US seeks to ensure that India doesn't
become the next China in the next 20
years. Right? That's always been their
objective and they've always taken
actions um along those lines. all the
subnational diplomacy and whatever
they're doing project K the regime
change operations in east and west
Pakistan all of that stuff it's all
aimed at towards containing India right
so the mask of well I've always seen
through the mask but now I'm glad the
rest of India is seeing it because of
Mr. Trump's uh activities, let's say.
Yeah. So, is a war coming? No, there's
no war coming. The US doesn't want war.
They know Pakistan can't win can't win a
war against India. The US won't go to
war with India. What's the what's the
need for that? What's the reason? No
reason for that. But they can use
Pakistan possibly to
to try and create problems with India.
But Pakistan obviously isn't in in any
shape to to create real problems for
India. If there's a full-fledged war, if
like if for example operation sindur had
gone on for another 3 days, Pakistan
would have been in ruins. Possibly
possibly we had already crossed their
their so-called nuclear red lines very
badly. We had crossed the nuclear red
lines. So their nuclear threat, their
nuclear bluff is gone. It's called
right. So Pakistan's nuclear bluff won't
work. We have crossed their red lines
massively during operation synindor. So
I don't see a war coming with Pakistan.
If a war does happen with Pakistan,
Pakistan will be in ruins. It will be a
smoldering set of ruins. Right? So a war
isn't coming. And if it comes, we'll
win. What should India do next? Stay
calm. Carry on.
Okay? That's what India has to do.
Whatever pain comes our way from the US,
swallow it.
Don't don't respond in an immature
manner. Stay mature, stay calm, carry
on. It's a 20-year slog. It's a 20-year
marathon for us. We have to build our
economy.
Once we are at a $15 trillion mark, $20
trillion mark, we're going to be a whole
different beast. We have to reach there
somehow anyhow the next 20 years. That's
that's the real work we have to do.
That's what India needs to do next. One
step at a time. We are climbing Mount
Everest. We are now at base camp and we
have to start the climb. So you don't
look up, you look in front of you. One
step, one step, one step, one, one foot
in front of the other and keep going.
That's what India has to do for the next
20 years.
Mr. Strange says why this late
announcement by the Indian Air Force of
Pakistani jets being downed. So the
announcement was made yesterday that
India uh destroyed five Pakistani
fighter jets in the air using the S400
system. Yes. And we also destroyed
several F-16s on the ground. We also
destroyed Pakistani Awax aircraft and
and so on. So this was announced
yesterday. Why wasn't this announced uh
once operation Synindur went into a
state of a pause May 10th? Why not then?
See, India was being nice to Mr. Trump.
It was a friendly gesture towards Mr.
Trump.
This would have embarrassed Mr. Trump
that his assets essentially were
destroyed. US F-16s, possibly US
personnel who were babysitting those
F-16s. It's it's embarrassing for the US
for a Russian system operated by India
to destroy American assets. It's
embarrassing. It shows that Russian
systems are superior to US systems. So
this was a friendly gesture towards Mr.
Trump considering the fact that India
and the US have a good relationship and
the two leaders Mr. Modi and Mr. Trump
are on good terms. A friendly gesture
towards Mr. from and what did Mr. Trump
give us in return? Everything we have
seen. So now that the gloves are off and
the relationship is is in the rocks, we
might as well announce it. So that kind
of is what happened, right? Okay. Anikit
Idate says, are we living in a world
with competent reader competent leaders?
Modi India rising India
Putin USSR
um Putin USSR to Russia Netanyahu
Netanyahu Xiinping Kavir Mle my comment
we have pretty competent leaders right
now uh who are the leaders I see as
competent but that would be
controversial well so be it uh Mr. Modi
Mr. Putin Mr. Xiinping definitely
very competent leaders. I would say even
Mr. Netanyahu is a very competent
leader. He's facing all kinds of
domestic troubles but that's a whole
different story. But overall he is a
pretty competent leader. No question.
Khavier Mille is doing a good job in
Argentina. He has shored up the
Argentine economy. Um
yeah that's what I can think of. Uh in
the EU I think Mr. Mong Mr. Mong is a
pretty competent leader himself. No
question about that. He's doing a pretty
good job overall of of uh overall of of
uh marshalling his nation through these
troubled times. So we are indeed living
in a in a world with pretty competent
leaders.
And the top three I would say are Mr.
Modi, Mr. Shei and Mr. Putin. I would
say Mr. Putin who has been in power
since what ever since Mr. Yelen stepped
down. Well, he is he's has the longest
track record. very solid very solid
track record and uh if he if when Mr.
Putin eventually steps down because of
advancing age when he eventually does
that whenever it is if he gets the
transition transition of power right and
he gives power to the right leader
somebody as as competent as him then
history will regard Mr. Putin will
remember Mr. Putin as Putin the great.
So yeah definitely one of the great
leaders that Russia has produced and Mr.
Modi probably India's greatest prime
minister thus far since 47. Mr. Xinping
is the current emperor of China. I think
he's also solid very solid very
competent from from his nation's
perspective. So yeah we are living in an
era of pretty solid robustly competent
world leaders.
Siddhant VMA says
chchhatchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchions
destroyed many Russian tanks via
guerrillaa tactics.
Chchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchchens
zassians are non-indo-uropean.
How did chachchna become integrated into
the Russian federation despite
historical conflicts and how did they
resist?
Is the chchen language a
non-indo-uropean language? The
sarcasians as far as I know are
indo-uropeans.
In English I'm not sure. Chachchans,
Dagistanis. Let's see if Chichchan is an
Indo-Uropean language. I am not an
expert on the Chchnian language. Let's
see
Chichchan language. What language family
does it fall under is the question.
Let's see. Wikipedia first of all. It's
a northeast Caucasian language uh or
Caspian languages. Uh
uh what language family is this? It's
one of the world's primary language
families. You are right, sir. Chchan.
The Chchan language is a
non-indo-uropean language. Fascinating.
What about the Ingusettian language?
Ingushetia language. English. English
language. Well, what language family
does it belong to? Northeast Caucasian.
Wow, you are absolutely right. Now,
let's let's see.
Okay,
let us see the Sarcasian language. Um,
you are utterly correct. You're utterly
correct. Even this is a
non-Indo-European language.
Fascinating. Fascinating. Right. You're
right. So, you're utterly right.
Cheschna, the Chchan language, the
English language, and the Sarcastan
language. These are non-indouropean
languages, which means that the these
peoples, these ethnicities are
non-indouropean. They're not part of our
our our
ethnicity, broader ethnicity, the
Indo-Uropean ethnicity. They're not. So,
so does that mean that Chuchchnik should
not be part of the Russian Federation?
What about the Yakut people?
What about the Tuven people? What about
the Tatar people? Even these peoples are
non-indouropeuropean people
but they are part of the Russian
Federation right and they they've also
had I mean the Tatars have had
historical conflicts with the Russians
18th 19th century oh terrific historical
conflicts with the Russians the Tatars
but they are part of the Russian
Federation and you know what they say in
Russia scratch a Russian you'll find a
Tatar inside that sort of thing because
they're all intermixed
um that sort of thing. So you see Russia
is a multi-thnic country. If you go to
the far east of Russia, you will see
people who look like Mongols
essentially, right? The Tuan people, the
the the people who even Mongols, you
even have ethnic Mongols in Russia. Um
Russia even has a completely Buddhist
part of Russia and so on. So um so
Russia has is that sort of a nation.
It's a multi-thnic nation, multicultural
nation. Islam is one of the primary
religions. Buddhism is also not
insignificant in Russia. Um,
and obviously Orthodox Christianity is
there. So, excuse me. So, how did
Chachchna become integrated into the
Russian Federation? Well, by conquest.
By conquest. Russia conquered all these
territories. It was by conquest and
obviously there was there was resistance
and like you say in the 1990s there were
two chuchchan wars
and Cheschna won the first chachchan
war. They became essentially independent
for a while and there was a huge setback
for Russia under the leadership under
the visionary leadership of Shri Boris
Yelen.
Yeah. Terrible. Yelin messed up and then
Putin comes to power and Putin straight
away goes back to war with with the
Chachchans and he wins the second
Chichchan war. He ensured that they won
and that's how Chachchna was
reintegrated into Russia and then
then you have the Kadov family which
comes into the picture and so on. You
can look it up the Kadro family.
Currently uh who's the leader of
Chachchna? The king of Cheschna it is
Mr. Kad Raman Kadirov.
But the original king of Chachchna was
uh his his his father Ahmed Kadov was
Kadirov. What was his name? I think it
was Ahmad Kadirov. Uh let's see
Kadrov.
Oops.
Kadov. Let's see. So Ramzan Kaderov's
dad was was Ahmmed Kadirov. That's
right. and he was assassinated with via
a um it was a bomb that killed him.
Anyhow, long story. So, so Cheschna was
integrated by force into Russia.
MK says, "Why is Israel cooperating with
Turkey and Azarbaijan against Armenia
and what are its objectives and
interests in doing so?" Well, excellent
question. I have obviously spoken about
this in the past in great detail but I'm
very happy to say to explain again. So
let's go let's go to the map first of
all because the map explains a lot. So
let's take a look at this region that we
talking about. Okay, we're talking about
Azarbaijan, Armenia. Here we have
Azarbaijan and Armenia. To the left of
your screen you have Armenia, this
nation here and to the right you have
Azarbaijan. Historically all of
Azarbaijan was part of the kingdom of
Armenia historically but that's old
history doesn't matter now. So Armenia
is sandwiched between Azarbaijan and
Turkier and Turkey. To the south of
Armenia you have an Indo-Uropean nation
which is Iran.
Now if you look at Iran the whole matter
actually revolves around Iran whether
you realize or not. See, Iran, Persia,
Iran is a nation that has lots of
enemies.
Uh, ever since 1967, Iran has said that
uh, Israel doesn't deserve the right to
exist. So, obviously, Israel takes it
very seriously and they consider Iran to
be their primary adversary in the
region.
And we know what happened recently,
right? The war between Iran and Israel.
So if you look at Iran,
about 50% of Iran's population is
non-persian.
Only half of Iran's population is
actually ethnically Persian. If you go
to Iran, you will see lots of people who
look almost European because they they
were brought in from regions like
Chichchna and other and other Turk parts
of Central Asia into Iran during a
period when Iran was under Turk
occupation just like India was under
Turk occupation. So Iran was ruled by
Turks for a long period of history and
they brought in all these foreigners
into Iran and settled them into Iran. So
that's why about half of Iran's
population is nonpersian.
So if we go to the northwest of of Iran,
okay, places like Tabaris, Tories, etc.
Uh you will find that this region is
called the east Azarbaijan province of
Iran.
And the people who live in this region
are ethnically Azaris, Azarbaijanis.
Okay.
So the the logic is this. If Israel
supports Azarbaijan
in its war in its conflict against
Armenia, then they will get favor from
the Azarbaijani population of Iran as
well, which means that they can spy in
Iran and could possibly potentially
cause problems for Iran.
So that should be the logic that seems
to be the logic that uh is driving the
Israeli cooperation with Azarbaijan and
obviously Azarbaian is supported by
Turkey. So that's why Israel is
cooperating with Turkey and Azarbaijan
in this matter against Armenia that they
will tell Armenia nothing personal but
we have this thing with Iran and we need
to have the Iranian Azaris on our side.
Okay. Hopefully that that explains the
way things are, why things are the way
they are.
Rishi Verma says, "Big fan." Well, thank
you so much. Thank you, sir. Uh the
question is, how can India be so strong
that no neighbor dares to mess with it
through military power, through economic
might or another strategy?
Everything
boils down to the economy. See if you
want to be a massive military power
you need a lot of money for that right
which means that your economy needs to
be massive enough to sustain a massive
military
so without a powerful economy you can't
become a powerful military power unless
you pour your entire economic might into
your military matters which Shri
Chingish Khan did essentially back in
the day because entire nation was
mobilized mobilized into the the the the
military of of of Mongolia. That's
that's an extreme example. We're not
talking about that here. We're talking
about India. We are not that sort of a
nation. So for India to be super
powerful militarily,
see if you want no no neighbor to be
able to to to dare to mess with you, you
need a super powerful military. No
question. But for that to happen, we
need a super powerful economy.
And not just a super powerful economy,
we need to be technologically advanced
as well. So that we are completely
self-sufficient in military matters in
arms, ammunition, all of that. Drones,
whether it's drones, whether it is
missiles, whether it is jet engines,
whether it's fighter planes, submarines,
nuclear submarines, warships, whatever
you can imagine, satellites,
lasers,
all of that needs to be manufactured
inhouse. So we need to be
technologically advanced as well. So if
we want India to be so strong that no
neighbor or anybody else dares to mess
with us, we have to first be a massive
economy.
Secondly, we have to be technologically
advanced at the cutting edge of
technology and that will make our
military so powerful nobody will dare
mess with us.
Okay.
Abishek says why the US did not stop
proxies for China did not prop
proxies for China like Pakistan.
Why did the US not prop pro proxies for
China like Pakistan? The US is pro
propping up Pakistan. See Pakistan is is
a mercenary nation. They will get into
bed with whoever is willing to throw
some cash at them. That's the kind of
nation it is sadly. Yes, they used to be
our people but they're not now. So
the US see Pakistan was created as an
artificial temporary nation by the UK to
serve the UK's geopolitical interests in
the region the subcontinent and the Gulf
region that overall big region but the
UK by 1956 or 58 became a second rate
third rate world power after the failure
of their su operation which was in
cooperation with the Israelis and the
French. So then the US took over the
mantle of the overlord of Pakistan.
Okay. And they propped up Pakistan. They
had various defense agreements with
Pakistan. And after Christmas Day 1979,
the US started funding Pakistani
terrorism
essentially and that was that fund those
funds were eventually used against
India, right? All of that. Um now around
2012 or something the US lost interest
in Pakistan temporarily and Pakistan
went into bed with China and the US is
okay with it. The US was okay with it
because no US assets were being exposed
to China. But now 2022 onwards the US
did a regime change operation in
Pakistan ejected Imran Khan brought in
Shabbash Sharif and now Pakistan is once
again a US vasal but it's kind of
cooperating with China also at the same
time and the Chinese have sold Pakistan
military equipment and so on. So
Pakistan is in bed with two partners at
the same time essentially but more with
the US. The US is the bigger daddy. Uh
so that's how it is. That's how it is.
So the US is propping up
what you can consider a Chinese proxy at
the same time.
Okay.
Survey Shwarma says what country will
leave NATO in 30 40 years? Germany,
France, UK? Or 30 40 years? I I have no
idea what will happen. Maybe we will
have
we have no idea what's going to happen
in 30 40 years. It's it's too far away
for us to inv
Mars by 2030 in in 30 years 40 years. So
today 2025 30 years is what 20 55 the
world will be a whole different place.
We will have flying cars in 20 255. We
may have extraterrestrials on earth by
2035. No idea. But what nations could
leave NATO in the next 10 years? I think
no nation will leave NATO in the next 10
years.
a situation where nations leave NATO
will only happen if the US is no longer
the primary sup primary power in the
world. Well, that would mean the decline
and and and end of the US empire. Only
then will we will you have nations
leaving NATO. So I don't see that
happening at least in the next 10 years.
30 40 years God knows no idea.
Okay.
Solo Leveling says if India purchases
purchases the Sukoy 57 or S500 given the
reaction to the S400 purchase do you
think this move may destroy any
remaining bipartisan goodwill towards
India?
Well,
if we have to purchase something for the
sake of our national security, we should
not be concerned with
whether we will
affect goodwill towards us in a in a
certain country.
Of course, that certain country is very
important. No question. So, look, now
it's clear. Let's let's assess the
situation right now. It is clear that
the that India has lost whatever trust
it had towards the US defense
establishment towards the US government
overall the Trump regime right whatever
Trump whatever uh trust existed has
evaporated because you can see that the
Pakistani military is is is showing a
lot of synergy with the US military
right now the aim is yesterday he was
meeting with American generals and all
so there's a lot of synergy between the
two militaries Right. And we know that
the Pentagon has always favored
Pakistan. So the whatever trust had been
built up over the last 10 years or so,
11 years that has evaporated. So India
is not going to purchase any more
American defense equipment. No F-35s or
whatever. But we do need fifth
generation fighter planes as a stop gap
measure until let's say 2035 when we
will have a certain number of
Indian-made fifth generation fighter
planes. So for we have a period of 10
years that we need to fill. We need a
certain number of fifth generation
fighter planes for the period. So what
options do we have? The Rafal is a 4.5
generation fighter plane. We need
something better than that because China
may be selling their their fifth
generation fighter planes to Pakistan.
Possibly that may happen.
So we need something. So if it's not the
F-35, what options do we have? It's
either the Rafal which is not fifth
generation or the SOA 57. Now people
will say that the SOA 57 is not as good
as the F35. I don't care. If we get a
full transfer of technology or even a
decent transfer of technology, it'll
help us tremendously and it's not a bad
aircraft. So most likely India will go
ahead and purchase the Suki 57 and the F
S F S F S F S F S F S F S F S F S F S
F500 most likely is a tremendously
powerful missile defense system even
better than the S S400. So if if it
makes sense for us, we should purchase
that as well. Um, look, the attitude and
approach of the US is already that of
containment towards India. Containment.
I don't care what they say. I don't care
what their politicians say. Oh, we have
goodwill towards India. We like India.
We would like good relations with India.
Blah, blah, blah. Words, words, words.
But what are their actions? Look at
their actions. Their diplomats, they
engage in subnational diplomacy in
India. They're trying to create fissures
and divisions within India. Their
embassy props up anti-India YouTubers.
That's one. Secondly, they they have
carried out two regime change operations
in our periphery, East and West
Pakistan. That is an anti-India move.
Third, their running project K Cookand
for Christ. So if you look at their
actions, their actions are those of
containing India. That their actions are
detrimental to our interests. I don't I
don't care what they say verbally.
That that so-called goodwill, bipartisan
goodwill is only verbal goodwill. Their
actions are all anti-Indian. Now look at
Trump and the tariffs. So I think we
should stop worrying about goodwill or
the lack of it and do whatever is best
for our interests. All right.
Okay. Premier League says, "Hello, Sar."
Well, hello Sar. You've defined what the
deep state, what the US deep state is,
but you've never named any members of
the deep state. Which people would you
suspect are members of the deep state?
Well, if I knew, I would say would that
I could that I could. If I knew, I would
name them, but I don't know who they
are.
I don't know who they are. I have no
idea. Look, okay, let's once again try
to redefine what the US deep state is.
Um the US deep state if it does exist if
it does exist would be an extra
constitutional extra democratic
extragovernmental
power center that controls
all the levers of power in the US if it
does exist and some of it may not be
extra governmental some of it may be in
the government maybe it's half in the
government half outside
so some of it would be so it would be a
small number of people who have all the
power. So for example, you know that the
US Federal Reserve Bank which is the
bank that essentially owns the US
essentially essentially well that bank
who are its shareholders
who are the people who own the bank that
is a secret now if you ask Google if you
ask your chat GPD or whatever they'll
say no it's not the case the
shareholders are other banks and so on
so forth they will give you a roundabout
story which will never give you the
answer. The truth is that it's hidden.
The US Federal Reserve Bank is a
privatelyowned entity.
Who are the people who own it? Can you
imagine the bank the national bank of a
country is a privately owned entity? It
should be run by it should be owned by
the government but it's not. So clearly
somebody owns it or some set of people
own the bank. Who are they? We don't
know. That's why I say I don't know. You
understand?
And obviously there are people who work
for the deep state. The richest people
of the world that we know of will
probably be the poorest people in the
deep state.
Uh that sort of thing. So you know I
can't answer the question because I
don't have the answers. But clearly
something like this does exist. I think
it's it's pretty clear to everybody by
now. The US is is just an autotocracy
masquerading as a democracy. The US
president really doesn't really have all
the power. The US president himself
serves somebody. There is this song by
Bob Dylan. Bob Dylan.
What is it called? You may be the devil
or you may be the Lord, but you've got
to you've got to serve somebody
or something like that. Yeah. So, you've
got to serve somebody. So, even the US
president serves serves somebody. So,
that's why I I don't really know who
those members are, right? I hope I
explained clearly why we don't know who
those people are.
Okay. Arun says, "How is it that Iran
which despite so Iran despite being
heavily sanctioned has advanced drones,
cheap and advanced roads, metros and
even indigenous supercars and they have
twice the GDP per capita income than
India.
Okay. So their GDP per capita is twice
that of India which is not a huge
difference.
But Iran is heavily sanctioned. They
have advanced drones and all that.
That's good. We also have advanced
drones and so on. That's fine. But look
at the roads in Iran.
Beautiful clean roads,
beautiful clean cities,
all of that. And look at the roads in
India in in the major cities in India.
Why is it like that? That's a question
we have to ask ourselves. Why? Why Iran
despite being heavily sanctioned and
facing all these trouble troubles has
such
so much better living standards than
India? In India,
the situation is horrible, abysmal. Why?
The problem is corruption. Allegedly,
it is alleged that India's number one
problem is allegedly corruption
which allegedly exists
all across the spectrum allegedly of the
Indian governance machinery allegedly.
That's the problem. So we have all the
money in the world. That's not alleged.
That's true. India has a gigantic
economy. The Indian government has
access to access to enormous amounts of
resources.
But how are the resources being used?
Where are the resources going actually?
Right? I think everybody can see what's
happening but you allegedly can't dare
to speak up.
So that's the major problem in India. So
my question is where is India's war on
corruption?
Corruption allegedly runs the entire
country. H the entire system allegedly
runs on corruption only. So where is
India's war on corruption? When is it
going to happen? That is the solution to
all of India's problems.
Mr. Sid says, "What are your top five
fighter jets globally?" The F-22 Raptor
is number one as far as I understand.
Best fighter plane ever. F-22 Raptor.
Okay. What else do we have? F-35. I'm
not going to put the F-35 anywhere. Um,
we have the Saab Grippen, we have the
Euro Fighter Typhoon,
we have the Rafal,
we have uh the Sukoy series, the Sukoy
30s, the Sukoy 35, Sukoy 57, we have the
Chinese J21 and J31.
Am I missing something? So, these are
some of the fighter planes I can think
of right now. We also have older
aircraft like the Mirage 2000 and the
the F-16s,
FA18s.
Um,
yeah. So, I would say the best of the
lot is the F-22 Raptor. The US won't
export it to anybody, not even to
Israel, apparently. Yeah. Wow. Would you
believe that? So, that's obviously I
would say is number one. Number two,
what could be number two? The the F-16
is a workhorse. It's it's worked very
well. But even but yeah, you know how
how it what happened in Pakistan. So I
would not put the F F16 up there. Um see
if you if you want me to give you
uh a rating top five, I can only give
you a rating of battle tested aircraft.
Theoretically, technically which
aircraft are better? Anybody can give an
opinion. But aircraft that are tested in
battle, battle tested aircraft, which
are these F-22, I'm not sure, but I
think F22 is still number one. Um, which
aircraft have seen action and and
they've come out on top? Mig 21,
I don't know about Mig 21. Um, the
Rafals have done pretty well in
contested airspace to some extent.
uh the Sukoy 30 MKI or Sukoy 30 I think
it's done decently well but it's not I
mean we haven't had a large scale war
somewhere where where you up where an
aircraft can be properly battle tested
so I'm not sure I think the F-22 Raptor
is up top and maybe the
yeah the other I can't really say maybe
the soy 30 35 series maybe the Suka 57
also may be
Uh, the Rafal is is a definitely a good
aircraft, but I'm not sure if it's right
at up at the top. And the European
fighter planes like the Typhoon and the
Grippen, have they ever been battle
tested? I don't know. The Chinese
aircraft, the the J21 and J31 or
whatever those are. JF7, we not we'll
not discuss that. That's that's a
variant of the MIG Mig 21. So, even the
Chinese aircraft aren't battle tested.
So it's really hard to give you a a
ranking of aircraft. The only correct
way of giving a a ranking of aircraft is
you can rank aircraft based on their
performance in war and battle. And
that's something we haven't seen and
that's a good thing that we haven't had
wars of that scale and magnitude.
So I don't know. I would say the F22 is
up top and then there's a whole bunch of
aircraft that are decent. Um
yeah, that's what I can say. I don't
really have a top five list. I have a
bunch of aircraft that are decent and
then this the F22 I think which is the
best one.
Okay. Wobb says will these tariffs
affect the IT sector? What IT employee
working in servicing company like in
city like Pune is supposed to do to
survive looking for next 20 years? Look
thus far the the tariffs are not aimed
at the IT sector thus far. Okay.
Trump hasn't imposed tariffs on the IT
sector thus far but it could happen. It
could happen. If that happens, then
India's IT exports become
either less competitive or
non-competitive. What could that cause?
What effect could that have? So, let's
say
someday in the coming days, Trump
decides to impose hypothetically, let's
say hypothetically, 50% tariffs on the
Indian IT sector. Hypothetically
that would cause tremendous damage to
the Indian IT sector because Indian IT
Indian IT services exports will become
highly less competitive compared to what
they used to be. Then what do you do?
Then what will Indian IT companies do?
They will lay off people.
They will lay off employees.
And that can be terrible
if you are an employee in an IT company.
So what do you do? I'm not sure what you
can do. If the if there are layoffs,
significant layoffs in the IT sector in
India, um that can cause a crisis in
India. Job crisis. Lots of highly
qualified, highly experienced, talented
people suddenly having to become
jobless. Typically they will first lay
off people who are on the bench, right?
We know what what a bench is, right?
First of all, they'll they'll lay off
those who are on the bench and then they
will lay off the junior programmers and
so on, junior staff. But yeah, that
that's bad. It it affects the the the
flower of our industry, the youngsters,
right? Um
so yeah, this is something that could
happen. What can I employees working in
a servicing company like Pune etc. What
can you do to survive?
Uh that's that's a tough question. What
do you do to survive? Um
maybe you can get into freelancing.
If you're in freelancing, I suppose if
you're working on a on a gig on on a gig
basis kind of thing, I don't think
there's a tariff on that. So if you can
if you can find clients of your own as a
freelancer, which is pretty tough itself
because if you're working for a company,
you don't need to go and hunt for
clients, right? The company has clients
and you work for them. But if you're a
freelancer now, suddenly you're in the
face with the prospect of where do I
find clients. So that's something you
will have to do perhaps. So yeah, it's
it's pretty tough. It's it's pretty
uncertain times right now. And what I
would suggest is that everybody who's in
the IT sector needs to take certain
precautions. Get your finances in order.
Have as much savings as possible. Have
options somewhere. Maybe your spouse
works in a different industry, different
sector, whatever. That's good. That's
that's that's a safety net for the
family. Um so I think you know bulk up
your savings. Uh invest in whatever you
can property or I don't I'm not giving
advice. I'm not giving any investment
advice. But yeah, you need to take
whatever precautions um you deem
necessary and and whatever is possible.
Yeah, because this this could happen.
Trump could possibly uh impose tariffs
on the IT sector which could affect both
nations. But well, Trump is Trump. He
could do that. So I hope it doesn't
happen and I wish you the best. I I it
will be bad for us and it I hope it
doesn't happen.
Nearby says, how do you see the India US
relationship in the future? It will all
depend on what happens in the next few
months.
What do I mean by that? It'll all depend
on what happens in the next few months
between Mr. Modi, Mr. Putin and Mr.
Shei.
If Mr. Modi, Mr. Putin, Mr. Shei can get
their act together, it will all depend
on Mr. Shei actually Mr. Xiinping. But
if that happens, if some kind of
understanding is reached and some kind
of economic grouping is is created then
well it's the end of the India US
relationship which is something we would
not really want because the US is a big
market and it's it's we have so many
people there. So it will also depend a
lot on the attitude and approach of Mr.
Trump.
So if the if the tariffs start biting
very badly at the US public at the
American public and if the economy is is
hit significantly then Mr. Trump will
have to back off
because he will otherwise lose
popularity but if he backs off then
again he will look like a weak
president. He is putting himself into a
corner but anyhow it will all depend on
the approach and attitude of Mr. Trump.
if he decides to impose even more
tariffs or if he decides that we should
go ahead and do some kind of a trade
deal with lower tariffs. Hopefully if
that happens then the India US
relationship will be okay economically
but strategically
whatever trust was there is gone. So
economically so the best case scenario
is that Trump backs down. Trump sees
some sense and his diplomats and our
diplomats they they work something out
and we we agree to some kind of a trade
deal with with whatever reciprocal
tariffs we need to apply on each other
that sort of thing and we carry the
relationship forward. That's the best
case scenario. So it'll be a decent
economic relationship in that best case
scenario but strategically there's not
going to be no trust. Now worst case
scenario is that Trump imposes bigger
sanctions on India. Then we decouple
from the US and then we find some kind
of way of u coexisting economically in a
beneficial way with Russia and China and
other nations who are willing to work
with us like Brazil and whoever else. So
that's not that of a good situation and
that is complete decoupling between
India and the US and then the US will
try and impose additional pain on India
using Pakistan or whatever else. So the
best case scenario is a decent
relationship economically. The worst
case scenario is a complete decoupling
and that will be bad in so many ways.
The shift room says, would you define
Israel's actions in Gaza as genocide?
What's the definition of genocide? Let's
go and find out. I would say look, let's
not define genocide or whatever. uh when
a nation faces a massive terrorist
attack like what Israel faced in 2023,
are they going to respond
disproportionately?
If the if if Hamas did not want whatever
Israel has done to Gaza, then they
should not have unleashed a terrorist
attack on Israel. Right? Uh after that,
what happened? Israel obviously has
essentially flattened Gaza to through a
certain extent. I suppose there would be
significant casualties and so on. It
would not have happened if if Hamas had
not done what it did,
right? A nation does have the right to
defend itself. And I will never ever
condone terrorism.
And why was Hamas in power? Because the
people of Gaza voted for Hamas, didn't
they? Did they not vote for Hamas? Did
the people of Gaza not know that Hamas
was storing all kinds of uh uh rockets
and whatnot? Did they not know that all
these tunnels existed? Did they not did
they not participate in in the terrorist
attack against Israel?
Yeah. So,
so I would say that Israel as the nation
that was at the receiving end of this
horrific terrorist attack reacted
disproportionately.
See, when you respond, when you
retaliate against your adversary, you
want the retaliation to be so
disproportionate that the adversary will
never ever dare to do it again. That's a
principle in warfare from time times
immemorial.
Right? So that's how I see it. That's
how I see it. I obviously
do not want people to suffer.
Nobody should suffer. But then if you
don't want to suffer, don't be
terrorists is what I would say. And the
same applies to Pakistan.
Suda Pakistan.
Thank you so much. Thank you sir.
Pratik says uh is Trump an example of
give a man power he will show his true
colors compared to his words first used
in first and second term.
Yeah. Yes. See there are lots of people
who are very nice because they are
powerless but the moment they gain some
kind even a little bit of power you you
see their true colors.
So you you are right. I would I would
answer your question with one word which
is yes.
Yash says this is not trade war against
India. It's a regime change operation
either demanded by the deep state or aim
in return for for favor for private
benefits to tapu you mean Trump for
minerals.
Well Trump the US would love a regime
change in India. They would love for
somebody else to come to power in Delhi.
They would Mr. Modi is so inconvenient
for the US isn't he? He's standing up
for He's standing up to the US. He is
friends with Mr. Putin. He's going to
China. He's going to meet with Mr. Xi
and see what can be done there. Mr. Modi
is standing up straight. He's not
bending down. He's not bowing down. He's
not caving in. He is extraordinarily
inconvenient for the US.
The US would want nothing more than
somebody else in the hot seat in Delhi.
Right? So um
and obviously when Trump imposes tariffs
on India there will be certain political
dispensations in India who will say that
this is a failure of Mr. Modi and I
suppose a lot of Indian idiots will
believe that because our education
system doesn't teach us how to think
critically right so they have been made
idiots by the education system they are
you see our people are the brightest in
the world but the education system turns
our people into into into fools and
idiots so you have to deprogram that
anyhow that's a different story um so
yeah if you if you have let's say
hypothetically politicians or political
parties hypothetically in India who are
on the deep state payroll and they start
this campaign this this uh this
narrative campaign that Mr. Modi's
foreign policy is failing and so on is a
failure and that can be considered as a
regime change operation. Yes, you're
laying the groundwork in the long run on
the long run for a regime change
operation. Uh so you are right from that
perspective. You're right.
Vijay Viki says Aim Munir is in the US
at a talk in Florida. He said that when
our existence is threatened, we will
take half the world's population with
us. What are your thoughts? Joke. Aim
does not control those nukes.
If he controlled those nukes then what
was he doing when we crossed his nuclear
threshold in in May May 7 8 what 8 9 10
whichever those three three days were
what happened we crossed the we crossed
the Pakistani nuclear threshold their
so-called nuclear red lines we crossed
them we on the last day
in a space of about 20 minutes we hit
what nine Pakistani air bases
our jets flying over the Pakistani air
bases. What happened to their nuclear
threshold?
Yeah. So that that bluff has been called
and it is almost guaranteed that
Pakistan doesn't really have nuclear
weapons of its own. Most likely those
nuclear weapons are American nuclear
warheads. That's how I see it. I have no
evidence to back it up. But I have a
brain which is a half decent brain at
least. So I believe those are American
nuclear warheads. So I don't think Aim
Munir will has the authorization or or
or the power to use those warheads
unless he's given a green light from
Washington.
Sudhindra Desai. Well, thank you so much
sir. Thank you.
Pratik Vaji, thank you.
Susant Badwaj, thank you very much. Very
kind of you sir. Thank you.
AVM says is it possible that Indian IT
companies not innovating is by design
and not because of their low risk
tolerance to be use of use in times like
these.
So we are in times like these right now
and Indian IT companies we know that
they have not innovated. Look first of
all we have to understand that we should
not overly criticize India's IT
companies.
We should not
be too harsh in our criticism of it of
our anti iting because they have
transformed India. They have given
employment to millions of Indians. They
have brought so many Indians out of
poverty into the middle class status.
They they have transformed the country
in the past 30 years. Right? No question
about that. Show me any other industry
that has that has done that. But it is
true that they have failed to innovate.
they have simply um stuck to the old uh
formula of of labor arbitrage and they
have done a good job at that but they
have not wanted to innovate. They've not
ever tried to develop their own
products.
Um so is this by design? Well, it's
obviously by by design and it's
obviously because of low risk tolerance.
The question is how can that be of use
in times like these? Tell me how it can
be of use in times like these. If Trump
decides I'm going to impose 50% tariffs
or 100% tariffs on India's IT exports to
the US,
then what what use are they in times
like these? What use are they? How will
they compete then?
But if they had products that the world
wanted,
if they had created products that the
world craved, then those tariffs would
not work. You see,
if they had created products, you know,
there so many softwares and apps that
the world uses, things that the world
can't live without,
right? But our our companies have done
none of that. They've produced nothing.
They're simply using that old formula of
labor arbitrage. So when you are hit
with tariffs, there's nothing you can do
about it. But when you have innovative
products that the world craves, even the
tariffs won't work. So yeah, that's the
situation.
Prashant says, "How to safeguard dams
after threats from Munir?" Well, the
threats are verbal.
We have safeguards.
And you see, look, it's it's pretty hard
to to safeguard.
You can destroy you can damage a dime
significantly with even an anti-tank
missile. I'm not sure if there's a
defense against an anti-tank missile,
right? So, it's pretty pretty difficult
to safeguard dams from threats.
Um I'm sure there are lots of options
that the the Indian armed forces have
even in these situations. But we have to
understand that these threats are verbal
threats
and all these threats all these
possibilities will be taken will have
already been taken into account uh
during the planning phase and and the
creation of the when we are planning the
building of dams and all that and the
best safeguard is that if you touch our
dams we're going to flatten your raindia
or whatever that's the best safeguard
and we can actually execute that we can
actually um you know if that promise is
we can actually execute the promise. So
that's the deal.
ICMBB says what's the story of the
Indian Tajakistan base? So we have a or
Farhore. What is it? Let's go to Google.
Uh Farhour. Let's go to Farhore. Farhore
air base. So there is this Farhore air
base in Tajakistan.
Is it operated by India currently? Not
sure. It's not far from Afghanistan.
Let's go to map. Yes.
So it is alleged that this is an Indian
air base. Let's go to the uh satellite
images.
Park farore whatever you want to call
it. And if you zoom out you should be
able to see
an air base somewhere here.
Where is this?
There has to be an air base. I have seen
that in the past.
I'll
maybe outside the city possibly.
Farcore,
Farcore Air Base.
Well,
so as you can see, it's it's rather hard
to discern
an air base here, but I remember seeing
one here.
So, that's one that's one place where
India allegedly
has an air base. It's on the border with
Afghanistan as you can see. As you can
see, this is the border with
Afghanistan.
Do I Okay, that's one. Okay, the other
one is AI
Air Base, Duchan Bay, Tajakistan. Where
is this? Now, this is a proper air base
as you can see. And if you zoom out, you
will see where it's located. Where is it
located? It is in a very different part
of of Tajakistan.
I So, let's zoom in once again. Do we
see any activity? We can see plenty of
military-looking aircraft over here.
Now, who operates these? These
helicopters look like Russianmade
helicopters.
And what do we have here? We have some
kind of fighter planes here. Three
fighter planes.
And we have hangars and whatnot. Okay.
So, it is alleged that India operates
two
um air bases in in Tajakistan. One is
Farhar, one is ai. I'm not sure to what
extent this is true or untrue. I'm not
sure the government of India has ever uh
um clarified the matter. So we don't
know but it is said that India has a
couple of air bases. I was not able to
find one in the in Faror but I'm sure
it's hidden somewhere. But yeah, so
that's what I can tell you sir.
Uh MK says Indians you say that Indians
are naive in geopolitics. Which nations
people do you consider pragmatic? What
have they done to demonstrate
pragmatism? See what do I mean by naive
in geopolitics? It means that you don't
understand how power works you don't
understand how international relations
work. Most Indians believe that by
shouting on on debates you are defeating
the enemy and uh so on
and you don't most Indians don't
understand
certain basic principles in geopolitics
which uh there's a whole bunch of
principles but the thing is this in
India you don't teach
things
okay let me reformulate that how many of
you know what what is the Indian
national interest.
Do you know what the Indian national
interest is? If I ask you to define what
is India's national interest, will you
know that? You don't. If you ask
Americans to define that, they will have
a pretty good idea of what America's
national interests are. If you ask
Russians to to define what Russia's
national interests are, they'll tell you
what those are.
And if you if you ask Indians, they will
have some opinion, but they will have
wildly differing opinions and the
opinions very often don't make sense.
So there's so much that Indians don't
understand and it is not the fault of
Indians. It is because we never teach
these things.
Is the national interest some kind of
vague undefined thing or is it something
that you can define with precision and
clarity? Of course, it is
right.
And and what's pragmatism? Pragmatism
means being realistic.
What is pragmatism?
It is what was the policy of Shri
Vishnak Gupta Chanaka extraordinarily
pragmatic.
So it's all part of our culture. It's
all part of our heritage. But we have
completely forgotten everything. How do
you demonstrate pragmatism? By sometimes
compromising. By not becoming emotional
about compromises when a nation makes
compromises. They're understanding that
there's a difference between the
short-term play and the long-term play.
There's so much that is is is within the
ambit of pragmatism.
So, you know, I can't explain all of
this or in a in a in a five minute
answer, but uh yeah, that's the deal.
Anonymous scientist says could not watch
latest episodes working on a paper.
Well, I wish you the best on your paper,
sir. And whenever it's out do let us
know. I would be I would be very happy
to see what the paper is about. So all
the best do well in the paper and it's
okay. You can watch the latest episodes
whenever you feel like it's all over
here. Right. All right.
Yash says one way of regime change is to
tarnish the image of a leader by using a
set of accidents air India economic
downturn to den demotivate people and to
vote for a deep state selected puppet.
Well who could that be? I wonder who
could that be? You are right.
You can see
a regime change operation takes time.
Takes time. It's not something that
happens overnight. You to create the
groundwork for that. You to create
a layer of sentiment, multiple layers of
sentiment to make this happen. And
eventually a few years down the line,
you can execute what you're trying to
execute. So you to prop up somebody.
Let's say you were to prop up Zalinski
as Zalinski is a great man. He used to
be a comedian, but he's now a great man.
So you prop up Zalinsky. You you have pe
people your your your media minions
write glowing articles about Zalinski.
You have your news channels praise
Zilinsky and lionize him. And on the
other hand, you whoever the current
leader is, you write articles, a slew of
articles criticizing and critiquing him
and and ridiculing him and all that. And
overall overall after a period of time
if you just continue this people's
opinion changes and then it's easy to
make something happen. So you're right
that's how it's done.
PLTP says what country will be rising
superpowers of next century. What chat
control EU online security act setup UK
the excuse me what
how chat control EU plus online safety
act UK setup similar laws could affect
India in the future. I'm not aware of
these things. But which country will be
a rising superpower of the next century?
We are in India obsessed with this term
superpower, aren't we? So let me define
what I mean by the term superpower. For
me, a superpower is a nation that can
intervene militarily anywhere on the
planet at 60 minutes notice.
That's my definition of the term
superpower. A nation that can intervene
anywhere on the surface of the planet at
60 minutes notice. Intervene militarily.
And now the definition will expand into
space also. So that's my definition of
superpower. So we Indians are obsessed
with the term superpower but we don't
even know what the definition is. My at
least I have a definition that I use.
When people use the term superpower in
the media or wherever do they know what
it means? Do they even have a
definition? I'm not sure which country
will be the superpower of the next
century. I have absolutely no idea. It
depends on so many factors, so many
variables. I would say that if we get
our act right, we could be one of the
nations. I mean, typically you only have
one or two superpowers. Will the US be a
superpower in the next century? I think
maybe not. Maybe not. We'll see. So, see
the next century is what 75 years ago?
75 years away. That is way too difficult
to predict. I would only say this that
there is something called the Lindy
effect. The Lindy effect says that if
something has existed for x amount of
time, it will continue to exist for
another x amount of time more. If a
play, if a movie has been popular for a
100 days, then most likely it will be
popular for another 100 days. If a book
has been popular for 20 years, then most
likely it will continue to to be popular
for at least another 20 years. Okay? If
a nation has been powerful for 50 years,
then most likely it will continue to to
be powerful for another 50 years. If a
civilization has existed existed for
10,000 years, most likely it will
continue to exist for another 10,000
years. So that way if you look at it, I
think India should be possibly hope I I
hope India is a superpower in the next
century. Hopefully this century in the
second half of of this century itself.
We'll see.
Godliness says I live in the west and I
have and what I have observed in the
past few years still the language wars
between the English, the French and the
Germans and many more are very relevant.
It feels like Europe is very divided in
in reality. Of course it is divided.
If you have been on the ground in
Europe, you will see how proud they are
about their languages and their cultural
differences.
Europe used to be a very insular set of
societies.
When I was a kid, if you met a French
person who spoke English and you tried
to speak English with them, they would
answer you in in French.
I don't speak English. I I they will
refuse to speak English because they
were proud of being French and they
considered English to be an inferior
language, an inferior culture. The
French and the English have this
long-standing thing, right? Thousand
years of enmity.
So if you live in the west, if you live
in Europe especially, there are language
and cultural wars between the English,
the French and the Germans, the
Italians, Italy, the Spanol, the
Spanish, even the Dutch to some extent
and so much more, right? Um, so it's
it's very real. Europe is actually very
divided. That's why I call the first and
second world wars the European tribal
wars. That's what it was. Look at the
chaos that led to the first world war
and and and the consequences of that.
It was all tribal warfare. Europe is
indeed very divided in in in reality. So
interesting observation that you that
you have made and I completely agree
with you completely.
Anonymous scientist says, "Sorry if it's
a silly question. Let's see." No, no, no
issues. Um will US policy to bully India
change after Trump or is it going to be
a new normal for the US? You see what
Trump is going to achieve is that this
is going to be a new new normal. the
damage that Trump is going to make, the
damage that Trump is inflicting and will
continue to inflict if he doesn't change
course immediately that damage will
become permanent and later if somebody
comes to power somebody else obviously
will come to power after him and that
even if that person asserts that I'm a
friend of India we that that
relationship will have gone way beyond
retrieval. So as of today the strategic
trust that whatever level of strategic
trust existed uh between India and the
US has evaporated. India doesn't trust
the US one bit now strategically one bit
and that is not going to change because
we have seen the approach and the policy
and and and the attitude of the of the
defense establishment how warmly they
they welcome that aim fellow and how
deeply they're synergized with Pakistan
there's going to be no trust no matter
what happens so economic relations may
continue they may even get better after
Trump but that strategic trust that Some
amount of it was built up over the past
couple of decades has evaporated. It's
over.
Yash says Munir may have informed Tapu
which I expect is Trump. Munir may have
informed Trump that to realize your
personal investments in Baluchasan
Baluch protests must stop. You must you
need to remove Modi to stop it.
I suppose he must have said that. I mean
it's a dream come true for Aim in
Pakistan. If Mr. Modi is no longer in
power right obviously obviously I mean
Mr. Modi the kind of actions he has
taken against Pakistan how how many
Indian leaders have done that the last
Indian leader to take any anything like
that sort of action was Indra Gandhi
Mrs. Indra Gandhi 1971 in which she gave
the armed forces the go ahead to
bifurcate Pakistan right ever since then
no Indian prime minister has taken any
harsh action against Pakistan and Mr.
Modi has done it right. So the from the
Pakistani perspective that that would be
a dream come true if if Mr. Modi is not
in power in Delhi. So I'm sure Mr. this
this fellow Munir must have exhorted his
his his boss Mr. Trump please sir sir
please
sir he would have done that. So I agree
with you. Aman Patanya says huge love
and support to you for you sir. Thank
you so much. Thank you so much. I I I
really appreciate that very much so. And
you know I I keep reminding myself every
day that you know it's a it's a
privilege that people want to listen to
you. It's a privilege if you are in a
position where people want to hear you
and listen to you. So I don't ever take
it for granted. I'm very thankful very
grateful to all of you for your
viewership for the fact that you turn up
to to ask me questions and and hear me
answer them. So thank you so much. I I
never ever take it for granted.
Feminist Slayer says, "After India
cancelled the US deal over GMO seeds,
what's what steps can India take to
protect its indigenous seeds from GMO
contamination and trade risks?" Great
question. So, one of the major bones of
contention is the that India has refused
to uh open our India's market to these
American GMO products, agricultural
products, dairy products and whatnot. We
will not allow this to happen. What
steps can India take to protect its
indigenous seeds? Well,
um see if you go to the US, okay, if
you're flying to the US, uh they have
some rules that you cannot carry certain
products. You cannot carry some seeds
and you cannot carry these things
whatever and you you to fill up a form
and tell them that I'm not carrying
anything. Then they'll still check your
luggage and if they find something you
they'll take some action against you. So
I think we will have to tighten our
border security
border security and and uh security at
our ports of entry. All the airports
where people come in from come from
abroad come to India from abroad. We
need to tighten the security ensure that
no seeds or GMO products are brought
into India. If anything is found we need
to be very proactively and vig
vigilantly confiscate and destroy that.
That sort of thing needs to happen. So
wherever we have ports of entry whether
they are airports or naval ports or
whatever we need to be super vigilant
at these ports of entry and ensure that
no such products are allowed in
and uh when it comes to imports things
that our companies are importing from
the US or whatever we'll have to be very
strict on that as well. So the
government will have to come up with a
set of procedures to ensure that we are
not in a situation where there is
contamination from GMOs right.
G says, I am moving to Khaledin grad for
studies. From a geopolitical view, how
do you see its role between Russia and
the West evolving over the fi next five
or six years?
Interesting. Very interesting place
you're going to kenrad. So, let me put
that on the on the map. Let's check the
map. It's an exclave. It's a Russian
exclave. Kuningsburg it used to be. And
after the second world war, Russia took
it over. After the allies destroyed it,
the allies flattened Khaledra.
Kuringsburg and then Russia took it over
and rebuilt it. So this is Khaledrad. It
is not connected to the mainland of
Russia. You see its neighbors are
Lithuania and Poland
and to reach Russia you have to go by
sea through the Baltic Sea and reach
sittersburg
or you have to go by air. So that is
Kalinindrad and and there have been
demands from Poland and other countries
that Kalinindrad needs to be
demilitarized. Russia should not be
allowed to to keep any weapons or or
armed forces there that sort of thing
and obviously Russia will resist that.
So Khalin could come under some kind of
pressure from the west but but Russia is
powerful enough to withstand that
pressure. So politically, diplomatically
etc. There's going to be talk of
kalinrad. It may be it may increase in
the coming years and nations like Poland
and various EU and NATO nations allies
or or assets of the US may uh may exhort
NATO perhaps or the US to take some
actions to demilitarize Khalinrad or
something or pressure Russia to do that.
So Khalinrad is going to be in the news
but I expect that Russia is
significantly powerful enough to resist
any pressure to change the status quo in
Kalinrad. So I think the next five six
years most likely the place will remain
stable and there will be no major issues
there. That's how I see it. So all the
best for your studies do well. All
right. Okay. SRR. Well, thank you very
much. They haven't asked the question
but thank you so much.
Ashish Karan says Prime Minister Modi
said we need to be technologically
sovereign and asked our tech companies
to innovate. Why didn't we do this
beforehand? Why do we always play
catch-up? Well, you see
we have been playing catch-up since
1947. In 1947 when the transfer of power
happened from the British to people in
India, India was a destroyed economy.
Utterly destroyed. And we have slowly
been rising from that. We could have
risen much faster if we had taken
certain steps in the 20th century
whatever. So what Mr. Modi inherited was
a well economy that was not doing very
well. And you know things have changed
overall and there are so many problems
in India. The one of the major problems
is this lack of self-confidence. The the
the
infamous Indian inferiority complex.
Indians feel that westerners people with
whiter skin are superior. The moment you
are in Indian person is in the presence
of a foreigner their their whole
attitude approach behavior changes. Yes
sir sir we are you are better we are
inferior that sort of thing that needs
to go away and this is one of the
reasons why we have not innovated.
Another reason for not innovating is
because of alleged corruption and
whatnot. So many issues whatever it is
it's watered down the bridge. We did not
do it. very unfortunate but now we
should do it.
No, we should do it. And eventually
there'll come a there'll come a time in
our country where we are no longer
playing catch-up when others will will
have to start playing catch-up with us.
For example, when it comes to missiles,
we have the most frightening missiles in
the world. We are the we are the best
missile producing nation in the world
today. Okay. When it comes to air
defense systems like the Akash, we have
the best battle tested air defense
system in the world. There are nations
who are playing catch-up with us on
these on on these fronts. We have to
extend and expand this umbrella to
everything else. So we are already in
some in some cases at the forefront of
technology
and that needs to move to other fields.
So eventually there there will come a
time if we get our things right where we
will not be the ones playing catch-up.
The rest of the world will be playing
catch-up. So that's the that's what
that's the challenge. The government of
India needs to create the right
conditions for this to happen as quickly
as possible and that's the challenge
that Mr. Modi is faced with and I wish
him the best because we would like this
to happen.
Basin says big fan. Thank you so much
sir. Thank you so much. Did you predict
the brrics currency will dominate the
USD in the next do you p do you do you
predict the bricks currency will
dominate the US dollar in the next 10
years? If so, how can that impact our
stocks? Well, there's no bricks currency
right now and in the past there has been
some talk of bricks currency but India
said no. But now things are different.
So will we will we as in will we India
ascent to the creation of bricks
currency? If that happens, that will be
a huge huge challenge to the US and
Trump will be super super upset with
that and he will impose sanctions on
everybody. So if we are in that stage
where the relationship between India and
the US has gone that far downhill, then
we may agree to a bricks currency being
created and that could be a significant
challenger to the US dollar in 10 years
possibly. I am not an expert on the
stock market so I have no idea how it
will impact stocks. But if the India US
relationship goes significantly downhill
then I expect the creation of a bricks
currency and that bricks currency could
in 10 years be a genuine challenger to
the US dollar. So let's see how that
goes.
Animesh Paul says did the US ever try to
vaselize China or did they try and fail?
Can India learn anything from China
along these lines? Love you great. Thank
you so much. Thank you. The US had this
great dream of vasalizing China. You see
the US used Pakistan in the 20th century
as an intermediary to start the the
channel the the communication channel
with Pakist with with China. So they
used Pakistan as the intermediary and
Nixon and Kissinger communicated to
Maadong that you know we would like to
have a dialogue and then eventually
Kissinger and Nixon reached China
Beijing. They met with Mr. Mao they met
with Mr. Shuin li and so on. And uh this
happened because the US saved China from
being nuked by Russia in 1969. The Usuri
river clashes when Russia USSR had
decided to nuke China. But the US came
in the way. So that led to eventually
this kind of this they the taunt between
the US and China and China decided and
the agreement that the the two nations
reached was that China would gradually
open up its economy to the US and China
would start manufacturing uh products
for the US slowly gradually that's what
happened it continued during the time of
then shopping and after then by the time
then shopping died the change was very
significant so the US hope was that you
know
if we integrate China into the world's
economy and if we make China more
prosperous than what it is. At that time
China was third world nation.
So if we achieve this change in China
then that will transform China and China
will become a liberal democracy and
hopefully a vasal of the US that sort of
thing. That was the great dream hope
ambition complete failure. So the
objective was to kind of vasalize China
kind of did not work right.
Buu says Makyavei versus Chanaka who's
greatest and more relevant. Look
Makyavei wrote a book
um
about how a prince a ruler can can
retain power essentially through amoral
means. Chanaka wrote a book on how to
run an empire. There's no comparison
between Makyavi and Chanaka.
How to administer, govern an empire, the
economy, the taxation, the
administration, the espionage, the
foreign policy, geopolitics, all of
that. Everything you can imagine how how
the emperor should comport himself, what
his daily routine should be like. Um,
all kinds of stuff. I mean, it's so
super detailed. Makyavari is nothing
compared to Chanaka. Chanak Chanak is
the greatest. No question.
Raj Lit says if India becomes becomes a
dictatorship what the what would be the
global impact. While if India becomes a
dictatorship and it it is run
efficiently it will have a gigantic
global impact. India will start behaving
like a whole different beast. um
decisions will be taken very fast and
implemented very fast and uh things that
usually took a long time to do would be
done very fast very rapidly and if India
becomes a dictatorship it means India
becomes an empire an imperial kind of
system which would be something like
what we always had so that the impact
would be massive globally India would
rise very rapidly as long as the the
ruler is is benevolent and
is is competent
Vishal roars says as is Brazil semi-
sovereign well you see if you are a
nation that that is in South America you
aren't fully sovereign you are under the
control of the US in so many ways
but Brazil is showing signs of
sovereignty because Trump is upset with
Brazil and has imposed 50% tariffs which
shows that Brazil is standing up for
itself at least to some extent so you
could say Brazil is se sovereign if you
look at the history if you look at the
Monroe doctrine and so much more and we
will see that no nation in South America
is completely sovereign.
Aris's manticor said we had ancient
protein fiber heavy millets and
essential tubers as part of our diet
along with wheat and rice. Should we
research this to try nutrition-based
genetic healing for our future
generations? I think we should
definitely explore
um cereals
beyond right and vis what am I say right
and what is right and wast
right and w rice and wheat so there was
something called the green revolution or
something in in India in the 19 in the
1900s in the 20th century and India was
a nation that was beset with famines
because of misgovernance and so so on so
the green revolution kind of helped
India but what it what the consequences
were were was that uh the nation became
dependent on just a few strains or
breeds of rice and wheat as the primary
staple uh cereal. Now we historically
had like you rightly say we had various
kinds of millets you know joar bajra and
so many different varieties of these.
These were part of our staple diet and
they that gave us so much variety in our
diet and those are actually I would say
better for your health and for digest
for your digestion etc compared to just
plain old wheat and rice
and they also taste good. So we
certainly should bring that back into
the mainstream. Right now most people
just eat wheat which is roties and rice
which is rice, boiled rice mostly,
right? But you can have all these other
fibers which were part of our
traditional diet and that would be
really good for our health. Uh would
that bring about genetic healing?
See one of the problems that Indian
people face a lot of the Indian
population faces is that it is uh
genetically more predisposed towards
becoming diabetic because of the two and
a half centuries of famines imposed by
the British on our ancestors.
So I think with good nutrition for
multiple generations we can weed that
out. I'm sure it can be done. So yeah,
we should certainly research our
traditional cereals
u with the objective of in the long run
weeding out these genetic defects.
Yash says after July 2024 deep state
change strategy made Trump part of deep
state of course September 24 world
liberty financial created foolish to
think that Trump won all swings without
blessing. Like I said, I first of all I
agree with you and I had said at the
time I had said that Trump most likely
won't win the presidency. That's what I
had said and I also said that if Trump
does win the presidency, it means that
he has kissed the ring. The kissing the
ring is an allegory to mafia movies like
the like like The Godfather. In the
Godfather, for example,
if you to to swear your allegiance to
the mafia boss, you have to go down on
your knees and you have to kiss the ring
that he's wearing on his whatever
finger. That's called kissing the ring,
which means you're swearing your
allegiance to the big boss. So I said
that if Trump does win, it means that he
would have kissed the ring of the deep
state. And that's exactly what's
happening in World Liberty Financial. Of
course, all of that. If you if you watch
my geost strategy episodes, I've gone
into great detail as to about Trump's uh
personal business empire and its
dealings with Pakistan and other
countries.
He's montecores why are the American
food products causing a rise in IQ
decline in mental disorders in kids? Why
are there people not doing anything
about it at all? You see, at some point
in time, the US economy became a
completely exploitative economy. The
pharmaceutical industry became an
exploitative industry. the food industry
became exploitative. They wanted to hook
their consumers onto the products. They
wanted to maximize their revenue with by
whatever means possible which had the
effect that all kinds of
processed food stuffs and processed
chemicals and whatnot became part of the
food chain. And if you I mean if you
look at a video of how for example
Doritos are manufactured you will see
the kind of chemicals and other stuff
that goes into it and all of this
obviously is not natural. It's going to
cause a decline in IQ or an increase in
mental disorders increase in obesity
increase in cancer increase in god knows
what things.
The food industry
exploits the people of America and they
are handin glove with the politicians
super corrupt. So that's what's
happening. You see why are the people
not doing anything at all? Because it is
not really a democracy otherwise
something would be done. You see you can
see the signs and symptoms of this not
being a true democracy. It's just
masquerading as a democracy.
K U Poll says, "Why is India arming
Armenia even when our ally excuse me
what ally?" Uh, let us not use terms
that casually.
Even when our ally Israel supports
Azarbaian, what are my thoughts on this?
First of all, Israel is not our ally.
India has no allies. What do we mean by
ally? Do you know what the term ally
means?
A a nation is an ally. If you have a
treaty with it, a treaty that explicitly
lays out
the rules of the alliance, the terms of
the alliance and both nations must sign
that treaty. That's when you have an
alliance and that's when you are an
ally. Both nations are allies. We have
no allies.
Please understand this my dear Indians.
This is another example. Somebody asked
me that why are Indians? What do you
mean by Indians are are are naive when
it comes to geopolitics? Well, this is
one example. I am not meaning to
criticize you. Okay? But this is an
example of that. I'm not criticizing
you. This is not your fault. We are not
taught these things in the education
system. So, it's not the fault of our
Indian people if they are naive
geopolitically. But that's why I am
doing what I'm doing. So, please
understand what does it mean to be an
ally? It means you have a treaty
alliance. You have a treaty with both
which both countries have signed. then
we have no such treaty with anybody. So
Israel is not our ally. We have good
relations with Israel. We have a lot of
convergence of interest with Israel. But
we have differences with Israel as well.
And I'll not go into those right now. So
this is one example. India is arming
Armenia. Israel is supporting
Azarbaijan.
Why are we arming Armenia? Because we
don't want this ancient nation with whom
first of all we have a very ancient
relationship. We don't want this nation
to be wiped out from the map of the
world. Secondly, if Armenia is wiped
out, it strengthens Turkey greatly. And
Turkey is an ally of Pakistan, not ally,
a friend of Pakistan.
Okay? And that will strengthen Pakistan
and that will hamper our friends, our
friends in Persia, in Iran. It's
complicated.
Okay. So why is Israel supporting
Azarbaijan? because they want to use
that to to influence the Azari
population in Iran to hopefully from
their perspective conduct a regime
change operation in in Iran. It's pretty
complicated. Pretty complicated. So
that's the deal. So you see Iran see
India and Israel are on opposing sides
in this matter. Are allies generally on
opposing sides? No, they're not.
Okay.
Uh
there's clear weaponization of laws and
commi feminism to destroy marriage and
family system in India. How do we save
ourselves from this attack? Lack of pura
masculinity makes us sucking sitting
ducks etc. Look this is not really a
geopolitics question but look you are
right there is all this happening and
how do we save ourselves from this
attack? We have to reform the education
system. If we teach the right things to
our kids from the very beginning through
the education system, nothing like this
will work.
Nothing like this will work. All this
weaponization of all this nonsense, it
won't work if our people are properly
educated.
You understand? You have to teach the
right things from the very beginning.
From the time a kid is 3 years old all
the way to the time they're in college.
If you take care of the education
properly, nobody can influence them.
Nobody can brainwash them. Our education
system is so weak. So and itself is the
problem and that's why this that's why
we have these issues in India. Your own
teachers and professors eventually teach
you all the wrong things. They influence
you in the wrong direction. That's the
problem. And our because you are
impressionable kids you'll you'll
believe them. That's what needs to
change people. That's why I keep saying
education needs to be reformed.
Right. Okay. Okay, we're going to end
this soon. Uh, Aries Manticor says the
US education system is being exported
being exported to the world has been
optimized to demonize their own young
men. That's right. So on a record scale,
the school college dropout rate of young
US men is becoming higher and higher.
That's true. That's what you can do. The
education system is so powerful. In any
country, the education system can
completely change outcomes for the
country completely. It won't happen
overnight. It will take 20 years, 30
years, but eventually you can completely
transform the whole nature of a country
through the education system. So the US
is a nation that's that's misandric
today. Men are secondass citizens in the
US. That's what's being done to the US
actually. In the US, they're demonized
men. No question about it. Um so young
men are disench disenchanted
and they're dropping out and so on and
they are trying to export this stuff to
India which is a geopolitical ploy once
again you see Sager thank you so much
sir thank you very much uh Saga once
again says how to deal with rising hate
versus Indians in Canada US Ireland in
East Asia where many worshiped the
Buddha but wrongly believe it was
Chinese not Indian
let's talk about First of all, the west,
Canada, US, Ireland, these nations.
Look, there's a wave of propaganda
against Indians on social media.
They demonize Indians. And this is being
done, this is not all accident. It's not
spontaneous. It's being done by design
to to change the way Indians are viewed
globally.
See, you know what Pakistanis do when
they go to Western countries? They form
grooming gangs, rape gangs and they do
all kinds of horrific crimes. Indians
never do crimes. But you will not see
any such hatred being spewed against
Pakistanis on social media while Indians
are consistently demonized, demonized.
And this is being done on it's it's not
random. It's not spontaneous. This is
all organized.
It's all well thought out. So this is
the situation and because of that you
you're seeing you know rising incidents
of of attacks or assaults or various
hate crimes against Indians in the west
whether it's North America whether it's
Ireland or wherever how to deal with
this I have no idea you got to be
careful if you are an Indian origin
person living there you've got to be
more careful that's what I would say
because this is going to increase it's
getting worse the US administration the
Trump regime is now talking about the
H-1B visas. How how Indians with H-1B
visas are stealing American jobs and
all. So once again, you can see more
demonization coming from the very top.
Indians will have to be very careful. If
you are a brownkinned person look like
an Indian person, you've got to be
careful. You will have to take
precautions that others don't have to
take. Yeah. Uh in East Asia, I don't
think there's that that sort of hatred
towards Indians. That sort of thing.
Yeah. Many people in East Asia,
especially those who aren't educated,
believe Buddha was Chinese because the
Chinese government has portrayed
Buddhism as a Chinese religion because
they have had Buddhism for the past
2,000 years, right? At least.
So, what can we do about this? Well, I
would say that the government of India
needs to take steps to to teach the
world to to remind the world that
Buddhism originated in India. It's an
Indian religion. It's one of the dharmic
religions and it is one of the facets,
one of the religions that are part of
the Dharmic umbrella and it's not just
the government of India that that needs
to do this. Us Indians need to educate
the world wherever possible. So that was
that's what needs to happen and another
thing that does contribute to a negative
perception of Indians is the way Indians
behave when they go abroad as tourists.
That needs to change. I mean the people
of Bali allegedly I hear are tired of
Indians because of the way Indians
behave there. I mean the Balinis should
be the first people to like Indians
because we are the nation where Hinduism
came from and the Balines people are
Hindus but apparently even they are
tired of Indians and their behavior. So
Indians when they visit other countries
need to learn how to behave in a
civilized manner. Just because you've
got some money doesn't mean that you can
now go and flaunt it and behave like
like absolute bo abroad.
Hyphen 2K. Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you. Arun says DJT is behaving
like a vendor who got haggled by an
Indian mom for 30 minutes and didn't
sell anything. Indian envoy may have
used their experience from roadside
shops here. I don't know what you mean
by that, but he is frustrated. Trump is
definitely frustrated. U the Indian
diplomats clearly have
negotiated very hard. They clearly are
very tough negotiators and that seems to
have really upset Trump because he was
expecting that India will cave in and
India will give him exactly what he
wants and he hasn't got anything of what
he wanted which was the vasalhood of
India. He hasn't got what he wanted and
that's why he's upset.
So yep India is standing up for itself.
Hyphen two cases I'm a truck driver in
the UK originally from India. Okay. And
all I do is listen to Ask Kabijit all
day long and it has changed the way I
think. Thank Wow. I'm astonished.
First of all, well, thank you so much
for for for
spending your valuable time listening to
me. Thank you so much. Um, and I'm I'm
I'm happy it has it has changed the
possibly the way you think. Thank you so
much. And uh yeah, so you you're in the
UK. You're a truck driver from India.
Well, thank you so much for for your
contribution and for for saying the for
for for communicating this to me and to
everybody else and uh what can I say?
I'm I'm very touched. Thank you so much
and I wish you the best, sir. Do do very
well in whatever you're doing in life.
All the best and I I would I look
forward to hearing from you again in the
future. All the best, sir. All the best.
Do well.
Ran Singh says, "How does the US do
regime change? Why can't India do it?"
That is a whole big story. How do you
affect affect a regime change operation?
Well, I would say look, I cannot tell
you the mechanics and dynamics of regime
change because it's a very long thing to
explain. But I would say I'll give you
some homework. Some homework. Okay? Look
up how the Euromidan revolution happened
2014 in Kiev. The Euromaidan coup that
was
executed by the US.
How was it executed? Look it up. Look at
just look at the chronology. Ask your
favorite Google or chat GPD or whatever.
Give me a chronological outline of the
events that preceded the Euromidan
coup or revolution. The events that
happened during the the coup, the
revolution and the aftermath of that.
Give me a chronological outline and
explain the involvement of US government
officials in that. Then you will have a
chronological outline of what things
happened in what what sequence and what
order. That's one example of a coup that
the US carried out. Another example is
the uh regime change operation in Dhaka
which happened more recently last year
which I had predicted eight 8 n months
before that sort of thing. Yeah. So
that's what you can do but they have a
whole they they they have this playbook
now they have got it down to a formula
the color revolution formula and that's
how they they they do it. They have done
so many such color revolutions.
Kapay developer says excited to tune in
to your latest adventures. Thank you so
much and I look forward to having you on
board. On board. Thank you sir. User uh
6362 says did Trump solve Armenia
Azarbaijan issue? Yeah. Well yes it
looks like he has at least for now
solved the Azarbaijan Armenia issue. He
has brokered a peace agreement between
the two nations.
I think it was the first question I took
today. He has brokered a peace agreement
between the two nations. Both nations
will immediately seize all hostilities.
They will establish diplomatic relations
and trade relations and a Trump corridor
will be created in the southern part of
Armenia bordering Iran
where the US will have exclusive rights
to minerals and they will build rail
corridor and whatn not. So the US will
get access to some resources there. So
that's how he has solved it. Let's see
how long it stay it remains solved.
Let's see.
Achinti Anand says, "What are the Indian
national interests in the gist?" Well,
to give you a very simple ones sentence
answer,
the Indian national interest is the
long-term security, prosperity,
stability of the Indian nation and the
Indian civilization.
So the the duty of the ruler is to
ensure
the long-term
stability, security and prosperity of
the people and the and the nation and
the civilization.
This includes national integrity,
territorial integrity, civilizational
and cultural and religious integrity
also
and so much more. Okay, that's like I
can give you in a very brief answer.
Kapay developer says, "How can India
ensure that the Balo situation doesn't
blow up in our faces like the LTE in the
1980s?" Well, how do we ensure that? We
ensure it by doing by not doing
what we did badly in the 1980s.
In the 1980s, we sent the IPKF to Sri
Lanka, the Indian peacekeeping force to
Sri Lanka, which was professional
soldiers, but we did not give them a
proper mission. See what does the armed
what does the Indian army do? What is it
specialize in? It specializes in
executing missions. What's a mission?
That's your target. You go there, you
get in, get something done, and get out
in this much time frame. That's a
mission.
You need to have clear objectives. You
need to have clear targets. You need to
have deadlines. You need to have
territorial targets and what not. Clear
delineated missions. That's what you
need to have. What happened for the IPKF
is that they were told you go and be
there. Job bad job. Be there. Be there.
That's it. They had no idea what to do.
They had no clear objectives.
The Indian armed forces were treated
like a police force and that messed up
things. so badly. So you have to learn
the lessons of the IPKF uh debacle
and not do the same thing in Baljasthan.
So when it comes to Baljasthan, we don't
have any armed forces there. So first of
all, there itself is the solution,
right? How will it blow up in our faces?
How will it and so on. So that's how you
do it. So how do you ensure something
doesn't go wrong? by first studying what
went wrong the the last time and doing
exactly the ensuring that you don't do
any of the things you did at that time.
That's how we do it.
MK says, "What repercussions or actions
might the US take if India purchases the
so-al 57 or the S500?" I suppose they
would impose some kind of sanctions on
India, more tariffs or maybe sanction
some some form of sanctions. That's what
could happen, right?
Yeah,
Shiva Prasad says, "What are
geopolitical?" Oh, no. Why are
geopolitical strategist videos not
getting focused just like yours and
Ankit Shaw right now? I have no idea.
Look, look, we have to understand that
this platform that we are using right
now, it is not an Indian platform. It's
a foreign platform. It's an American
platform. We have to acknowledge that
fact. We have to respect that fact. We
have to respect the fact that this
platform
gets to set the rules of the game.
We don't get to set the rules of the
game. They get to set the rules of the
game. And they will obviously not like
people who educate the world about
things that are detrimental to their
national interest,
right?
Um that sort of thing.
Now they are treating India as as kind
of an adversary nation, a nation that
needs to be contained. And if if Indian
geopolitical strategists or analysts or
whatever are educating Indians about
these things, well, they will not like
it. So they may suppress those channels,
suppress the viewers and subscribers and
whatnot. That sort of thing can happen.
And I would say that it's their
platform. They have the right to do it.
You understand that? So that's the
reason why I have decided to pull the
geostrategy series out. I'm not doing it
anymore on YouTube. I respect that this
is their platform and they have the
right to do whatever they want. And if I
say things that are not in line with
their national interest, they will not
like it. So that's how it goes. So if we
don't want to be in the situation, we
need to have our own platforms. Right?
That's how it goes. Technological
sovereignty.
Arun says why how different is Bali
Hinduism? Why is it different? I'll tell
you what, sir. You go to different parts
of India, Hinduism is different.
You go to Kashmir, Kashmir shvite shaism
is super different
from uh shaism the the worship of Lord
Shiva in Tamil Nadu
Gujarat is where you had Lord Krishna's
kingdom Dara lots of Gujarati people are
vehnov if you go to Assam or Manipur the
Vishnuism there is very different from
what you have in Gujarat
do you understand I think I've answered
your question right here now if you go
further ahead if you go to Indonesia IA
Indonesia used to be a Hindu nation,
Hindu Empire, the Majapahit Empire.
Their version of Hinduism was their own
version of Hinduism. Like any different
geography, you will have different ways
of of practicing the culture, the
civilization, the religion. So that's
how it was, right? It's pretty
different. They have their own ways of
of of worshiping our gods, the same gods
as us, but in a very different way,
different shape and form. And that's the
beauty of Hinduism. It is so diverse. It
is so democratic, right?
Ritik says, "My views on Maharashra CM
driving Islam." I am not aware of that
and I don't really have any views on
that. I'm so sorry. Yeah. Ankita says u
if no in India corruption is not looked
down upon unfortunately instead people
boast of their out of proportion income
or assets protocol money. Just a
statement. I'll tell you that. Why is it
so? Allegedly. You have to use the word
allegedly. Um
there is no action that's taken
unfortunately against corruption
when someone is caught with you know
assets that obviously were allegedly
obtained through illicit means let's say
hypothetical case I'm not aware of any I
may be aware but hypothetical case some
IAS officer is caught with 50 cr rupees
hypothetical scenario clearly that their
income can't support that sum of money
so where did it come from obviously
allegedly corruption. What happens?
Suspension. Not not termination of
employment. Suspension and after some
days quietly they come back into service
and they are posted somewhere else.
Well, they will start the same thing
again. So that's how the system is
allegedly run. The entire system
bottom to who knows how to how far up,
right? The entire the whole country
allegedly runs on corruption. So when
this is the system that runs the country
and there is no action taken against
that then people will boast about it
obviously right the moment pe the the
the government starts taking action
against this well things will change.
Akash says big fan. Thank you sir. Thank
you very much. How might the AI arms
race shape future alliances and
conflicts given current US and Chinese
advancements?
uh does India stand anywhere? See, right
now India doesn't stand anywhere. Okay,
India doesn't have its own EI systems,
LLMs or whatever. As far as I know, as
far as I know, uh but India could
develop something in the next two months
also. It's not that hard to do it. Uh
but right now, we don't don't really
figure or stand anywhere. How might the
AI arms race shape future alliances and
conflicts?
um it's going to be a couple of two
three countries that will lead the world
in AI and they will make their AI
services and products available to
everybody else at a price and uh not the
full technology of course but export
versions let's say
and let's say you have the US
so they will make their
LLM services available LLM and other
services available image generation
video generation whatever services
available at at various different price
points to the world and they will
compete with other nations like China.
The Chinese also have some some products
like what is it Deep Seek R1, R2 and
what else? They have something called
Manus and some other things as well. The
French have Mistal. So everybody will
compete to make money.
So it will shape the world in that sort
of sense. alliances. Well, in an
alliance, whichever nation is the most
advanced in AI is going to rule the
alliance. So, when it comes to NATO or
the EU, it's going to be the US that
that obviously is in the lead and nobody
is even close to the US. So, they will
continue to dominate the alliances. See,
in an alliance, the most powerful nation
dominates everything and gets to set the
agenda and the rules. So, those
alliances will be dominated by the
nation with the most powerful AI systems
because then they can do whatever they
want. Um so when it comes to EU and the
NATO uh the EU and NATO the US will
dominate because they're not just
militarily most powerful, economically
most powerful but also technologically
most powerful and they are the nation
that is at the forefront of AI. When it
comes to let's say any alliance that's
that involves China, well China will
lead that alliance. BRICS is not an an
alliance. BRICS is just a coalition of
nations, an economic coalition. So yeah,
that's that's how it's going to go. But
eventually it's going to be a couple
maybe two or three nations that will
lead the world and rule the world
because their AI advancements will go so
far ahead that nobody can catch up
eventually.
Yash says so-called democracy is so
manipulable. China and Russia knows this
and resisted themselves from western
puppets. Only way for India to get out
of the mess is not being democratic
nation. Well, we are very far from not
becoming democratic. We are very far
from that. But yeah, you're right.
Aradhi Pandit says, "Is Trump a Russian
asset? His actions justify it?" Who
knows? Who knows? You never know. You
never know.
Uh, Premier League says, "Hello again,
SAR. If the US has a deep state, do one
party states like China, UAE, Saudi
Arabia also have have their own deep
states?" Not really. Not really. The US
is special. It has a deep state which
and and and the facade of democracy
hides who really is wielding the livers
of power. That's what the Anglo-Saxons
have done in the past couple of
centuries. They have very cleverly
hidden their means of power.
That's what they've done. So the US does
have a deep state. I think that's very
clear to everybody. One party states
like China. China doesn't have a deep
state. it its power is it lies in the
polit bureau and top leadership of the
Chinese Communist Party as clear as that
there's nobody hidden behind behind some
curtain somewhere um Saudi Arabia the
royal family is the power there's nobody
hidden behind them of course they the
bigger power is the US and that they
have to acknowledge but overall in in
Saudi Arabia itself it's the royal
family that is the power and currently
it's the crown prince Mr. Muhammad bin
Salman who has who is the most powerful
person. So they don't have the deep
states. It's the US that has a deep
state.
Okay, we'll take a couple more
questions. Adit Kumar says, can India
sign a Sukoy 57 deal while Putin visits
India? And my second question, did we
kill two Turkish drone pilots during
Operation Synindor? I think there's a
possibility that India may sign a deal
for a for certain number of Suka 57
fighter planes when Mr. Putin visits
India. It's a possibility. I'm not
guaranteeing it will happen, but it's a
possibility that exists. So yes,
it can happen. Secondly, did we kill two
Turkish drone pilots during Operation
Synindur? It is possible. I am also
hearing some chatter about that. Is it
confirmed? No. Is it possible? Oh, it's
very highly likely. It's likely. That's
all I can say.
Uh Arun says about Bali Hinduism. I
heard that they were forced to be
monotheistic and they chose Brahma
um to represent the god. I can't find
the truth online. Vicki has just two
lines. Okay, I'm not sure about that.
See, Indonesia has been an Islamic
country for quite some time, right? Uh
and Bali has remained Hindu. It's
possible they may have come under some
kind of pressure to portray themselves
as a little more monotheistic as such,
which is something Hindus can do. See we
Hindus can
can believe in a 100 different deities
and gods but we can also say that all
these different gods and deities are the
representation of one great deity that
sort of thing. So Hinduism is a very is
very flexible religion that way. We can
believe in a supreme deity. We can
believe in a lots of different lots of
different deities. Historically our our
religion has evolved so much. We used to
have one great god earlier the pitru the
great skyfather whose consort was pritu
mata. We just had two major gods back in
the day even before the rigidic age.
Then things changed and it it's evolved
so much over the thousands of years or
the millennia. So I'm not sure about
this but it's possible. I think it it
kind of makes sense that in a
monotheistic country you may for you
know face some pressure of this kind.
Okay, that brings me to the end of
today's questions. I'm going to end it
here. Uh okay, one last question I will
take from Aradhyda Pandit. Uh I am a CA
student, 18 years old. Advice. Okay,
what advice can I give you? You are 18
years old. Your life is just starting.
Okay, my advice is work as hard as
possible.
Don't work over hard. Work work smart
and uh learn real skills. The education
system is is going to be something you
will need to go through because you need
degrees and all but the real skills you
need to learn are are the skills that
really matter in the real world which is
interpersonal skills. You need to know
how to deal with people. You need to
know how to learn new skills as soon as
as required. You need to be able to
solve problems in whichever field you
are. So these are the things the real
world skills that's what you need to
focus on. All right sir. All the best.
Okay. I'm going to end it over here.
Thank you so much for all the questions.
We have way overshot past 2 hours, but I
enjoyed this. Thank you so much for the
questions and I'll end it here. Keep
asking questions. Keep keep learning.
Keep raising your standards and I look
forward to seeing you in my next live
stream. Thank you everybody. Take care.
I'll see you soon. Bye-bye.